<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>UCAN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org</link>
	<description>Youth who have suffered trauma can become our future leaders</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 19:10:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 7</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 16:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6481</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest. Finance, the future of Chicago, and how young people from any background can find a career. In this episode of our interview series, Yusuf Aljabri, a UCAN participant and aspiring...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/" title="Read Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 7">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 7</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L9Tq2lK8ciE" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p><strong>Finance, the future of Chicago, and how young people from any background can find a career.</strong> In this episode of our interview series, Yusuf Aljabri, a UCAN participant and aspiring finance professional, sits down with Kourtney Gibson, President of Loop Capital Markets and a regular commentator on CNBC, to explore how she made it to a leading position in the financial industry, what advice she has for young people interested in entering the field, and why she feels the financial industry is important to the future of Chicago.</p>
<p>Other Episodes can be found <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Yusuf Aljabri:  Ms. Gibson, would you please introduce yourself and tell us a little bit more about Loop Capital Markets and what it is that you do here.</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Kourtney Gibson:</strong>  I&#8217;m Kourtney Gibson, President of Loop Capital Markets. We’re one of the largest privately held investment banks in the country and the largest minority owned investment banking firm. What we do here at Loop Capital is underwrite on behalf of institutions, ranging from public institutions like the city of Chicago and Chicago Public schools through corporations like the Exelons of the world.</p>
<p>We also trade stocks and bonds in the secondary market on behalf of institutional investors across the country, ranging in size from the BlackRocks of the world (which is the largest asset manager on the planet) all the way through smaller asset management firms you may have never even heard of before. We are an investment bank and brokerage firm.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:  So, did you always plan to go into finance? And if not, what changed your mind?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong>  Absolutely not! I was going to be a bilingual pediatrician. Then I went to undergrad at the University of Miami and I got into the business school – I tested in, and I said, “Well, this business thing could be interesting.”</p>
<p>I was fortunate enough to have interned here at Loop Capital when I was 16 years old, so I had an introduction to business and finance – but I still was going to be a doctor initially. Then, after taking some business courses, and continuing to intern here as well as at Morgan Stanley in New York, I decided this might be the path I want to pursue. So, I decided to stick with finance, majoring in international finance and marketing, with a minor in business law (you always have to know the legal side of things) and I have been at Loop Capital ever since.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>Cool, so what kind of jobs are there at Loop Capital?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> Take your pick. When you think about an investment bank there are a lot of things that make it go, from the technology and working in IT to the accounting and finance functions that we have here, through marketing, through creative writing…there are a lot of things you can do here – and that&#8217;s not even on the business side yet.</p>
<p>On the business side there are a number of opportunities. At the entry level, generally speaking, is our analyst program, and from the analyst level you go into being an associate, then a VP, SVP, Managing Director…As a matter of fact, if you wanted to become CEO here one day the door is open for anyone that has the will, the aptitude and the integrity to get the job done.</p>
<p>There are a number of things you can do here at the firm also from a specific perspective. We have bankers, we have traders, we have sales people on the business side, and on the administrative side is human resources, accounting, legal, IT, marketing, you name it.</p>
<h2><strong>YA: So, what should someone like me who aspires to be into business and finance do right now as they prepare for their future careers?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KA:</strong> The number one thing you start with – and I don&#8217;t care if you want to be the CEO of a company or you want to go do something totally outside of finance – the number one thing is your education. If you can get the grades right that sets the stage to opening the door for you to anything that you want.</p>
<p>In addition to that education you need integrity. People have to know and believe that you are a person of your word and that you do the right thing. Don&#8217;t ever sacrifice that for anything; everything else will follow suit, but you have to have integrity.</p>
<p>And you have to work hard. So, as you’re working hard, whether that is at school or whether that is in after school programs, doing the best, being the best will help to shape your future (in my humble opinion), to be able to open the door for you on the business side of things.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:  What was your motivation throughout your college years,  and how did that get you to where you are today in terms of your career?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong>  What motivates me? I am a woman of faith and family. I am very strong in my faith and I love my family, and I feel like I need to be successful in order to make sure that I can make my family successful and generations to come. That motivates me. <br />I want to be the best that I can be for – and it sounds really clichéd – but for the world, ultimately. If I can do my little part in this little thing called life, hopefully I can impact this world in a positive way.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>I&#8217;ve seen that you are a regular guest on CNBC. How is that, being the face of Loop Capital Markets? Is there any pressure when you go on that show and have to represent the company?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> There&#8217;s tons of pressure!  Not only am I feeling like I represent the company, but there are a lot more weights that I feel are on my back at any given point in time. And so, I&#8217;m nervous every time I go on – but that nervousness actually forces me to prepare.</p>
<p>When you think about the fact that there are young girls and young boys that are looking on that screen and I may be the only person of color or the only woman that&#8217;s a person of color that they see that entire day on that network. It&#8217;s important to me that I make sure they understand that they can do this, too – that I am up there doing just as much and saying and being as on top of it as all the other gentleman that are sitting around me at those tables.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong> <strong>How do you see the financial industry being important to Chicago and the future?</strong></h2>
<p>KA: I think the financial services industry is a part of the fabric of this community.  Aside from the money that moves within a lot of these institutions, the financial institutions have an obligation and an ability – and candidly they have been stepping up to the plate  – around actually working with communities.</p>
<p>Think about a lot of the not-for-profits that are here in the city…think about the different entities that help and give back, whether that be through internships, donations, different programs. Many of those not-for-profit boards consist of people that come from the financial services industry, from the Jim Reynolds of the world to the John Rogers of the world to a myriad of other CEOs that are across this city. They really do get behind making Chicago the epicenter of financial services – and making sure that everyone is participating in that economic development.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>Do you think it is important to find minority youth that are interested in finance, and try to teach them things they may not be exposed to coming from the places that they do?</strong></h2>
<p>KG: Definitely, and many of the institutions across the city have internship programs. I sit on the board of the Chicago Scholars Foundation where we just launched a program called Emerge, which helps to place students of color, first gen students, low income students, into companies across this city, to expose them to financial markets and other companies like Loop Capital.</p>
<p>I am sitting here as living proof of an internship program. I think back to when I started interning – the CEO paid me out of his pocket.  And John Rogers and Melody Hobson over at Ariel Investments have started a school. So when you think about the commitment here, the desire for minority students in particular to have exposure to this business, we are following suit via not only our wallets, but also our time, effort and energy, to make sure that we’re not the last faces of color you see in these seats – and that we continue to grow and foster students across this city.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>Are there some of those internships here at Loop Capital?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> Definitely. Right now, our internship program brings in either sophomores or juniors in college. We have a huge internship talent pool – over a thousand applicants this past year that wanted to work at Loop Capital. Unfortunately, we couldn&#8217;t take them all in, but we do usually have between 20 and 30 students every single summer that we bring in to expose to investment banking.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong> <strong>What are some of the things that they do within the internship?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> It varies – whatever we need. Candidly, if I needed to go do something that isn&#8217;t normally what you would see a president do – say we have a pitch and everyone else is working on something – I&#8217;ll go in the back and put the books together.</p>
<p>It really is a roll-up-your-sleeves kind of business, and at the end of the day the ultimate objective is to add value to your clients, which ultimately adds value to the firm…which ultimately makes sure that we can offer jobs and internships to folks such as yourself in the future.</p>
<p>There are a myriad of things that interns here get exposure to, from putting together those pitch books to burning the midnight oil running models and working in Excel and PowerPoint. And we bring our interns to meetings – whether it&#8217;s with a CEO or the mayor of the city, we&#8217;ll bring our interns to expose them to what actually happens at the other end. So, you’re working all night running models and doing pitch books – well, how does that come to life in a meeting? We really try to expose our students to the full gamut of what it is to work at an investment bank.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>I&#8217;m a junior in high school and I have to deal with a lot of things, such as school and taking the SAT, but also, I want to enhance my understanding of the financial industry. Is there any advice you have for me that I can be able to manage both my school and learning about the financial industry?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> Prioritize.</p>
<p>Like I said – and I don&#8217;t care if it&#8217;s Loop Capital, if it&#8217;s Morgan Stanley, if it&#8217;s Citadel, if it&#8217;s Ariel – when you first come through that door you have to be on par and as good, if not better, than the folks who are already in that job. The first thing people are going to say is “OK, what’s is your GPA? What were your test scores? And maybe you didn&#8217;t go to Harvard or Yale, and that&#8217;s OK – but you went to school and you worked incredibly hard, you got great grades ,you were active and involved. You were involved in your community, and you showed an interest early on in this business.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s how you shape that total package that then comes in the door says, &#8220;Hey. I&#8217;m the person you want to hire.&#8221; You want to make sure you’re doing those things that give you a leg up in this world. So, if you want to be a fund manager and run your own portfolio, look at what the background is of those fund managers you aspire to be like. Then say, <br />“How can I put my career path on par with theirs? What did they do to get to where they are, and how can I put myself in a position to do similar things?</p>
<p><strong>YA:</strong> Thank you very much Ms. Gibson – thank you for being here today and allowing us to interview you.</p>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 7</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chance Connections to Deepened Relationships</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 18:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6434</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>By Andrea Lee, MPA, Manager of External Affairs April was National Volunteer Month, which to me, is a month of possibilities: possible connections, possible relationships, possible awakenings to one’s own city. I am dedicated to connecting community members to UCAN’s programs and people in meaningful ways. Through these relationships across geography, wealth, age, race, and...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/" title="Read Chance Connections to Deepened Relationships">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/">Chance Connections to Deepened Relationships</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>By Andrea Lee, MPA, Manager of External Affairs</em></p>
<p>April was National Volunteer Month, which to me, is a month of possibilities: possible connections, possible relationships, possible awakenings to one’s own city.</p>
<p>I am dedicated to connecting community members to UCAN’s programs and people in meaningful ways. Through these relationships across geography, wealth, age, race, and everything else, we build empathy and see each other’s humanity beyond our facades.</p>
<p>Case in point: A chance connection last fall has led to a supportive bond between a community member and a young person living in UCAN’s Diermeier Therapeutic Youth Home. I happened to sit beside a woman at the North Lawndale Community Coordinating Council’s (NLCCC) meeting to launch their Quality of Life plan, to which UCAN is a key contributor. She mentioned she wanted to get involved in North Lawndale, so I learned that her name is Kenya Harris and we setup an appointment to discuss mentorship at UCAN. Today, she is the mentor to a 13 year-old who lives at the Therapeutic Youth Home and who has no other community supports or family. When I asked Kenya what it feels like to be a mentor, she responded:</p>
<p>“Being a mentor makes me feel good and is truly a blessing.  To be part of a support system to a child in need is very rewarding.  I feel lack of support is the primary reason many people have difficult times in their lives.  For me, being a mentor is about letting my mentee know that she has my support and I care.”</p>
<p>The relationship can get complex, and the mentee sometimes asks for more than a mentor can give. I asked Kenya what was challenging about being a mentor, and she wrote:</p>
<p>“I never want her to feel like if I’m unable to do something it’s due to lack of care.  So, I’m currently in the stage of creating healthy boundaries through communication so that she knows I care and if it’s something with in my powers to do, I will.” <img class="size-medium wp-image-6438 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-268x201.jpeg" alt="" width="268" height="201" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-268x201.jpeg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-768x576.jpeg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-320x240.jpeg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-966x725.jpeg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-720x540.jpeg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-290x218.jpeg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-369x277.jpeg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></p>
<p>Sometimes, it’s a chance connection with a large institution, like the University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC). On a whim, UCAN applied to receive products made by students during “Make Mondays Matter,” a few hours oncampus when volunteers assemble goods for distribution. This led to 40 students supporting one of UCAN’s close partners, Stone Temple Baptist Church, during UIC’s MLK Day of Service, and then painting walls and completing a variety of projects at UCAN Academy  Grand during UIC’s Day of Service on April 13. Kennedy Hayes, a UIC graduate student in public administration, took some time recently to reflect on what UIC’s engagement with UCAN has meant to their students.</p>
<p>“Students have been able to see all of the ways that they can get involved so close to campus. UCAN covers so many projects that students can see and work with the issues that are happening in their own community.”</p>
<p>Kennedy also considered what it meant to work with each other, as we are geographically close but different in aims.</p>
<p>“It is vital for UIC to be more than a stand-alone university in the middle of Chicago. Integration with the surrounding community is so important for a thriving and successful population.”</p>
<p>Wrapping up National Volunteer Month is bittersweet. While the volume of projects would be difficult to maintain over the year, these examples highlight volunteerism’s ability to bring individuals and institutions together toward shared goals and a vision for a more cohesive society.</p>
<p><em>Check out our events during National Volunteer Month on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/UCANchicago">@UCANchicago</a>. </em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/">Chance Connections to Deepened Relationships</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>150 Years Later&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 16:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6412</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Things that turn 150 years old in 2019: The Periodic Table Professional baseball UCAN! We happen to think UCAN is as innovative and original as our 150 year-old compatriots. But how does one innovatively celebrate such a milestone? We kicked off our celebrations exactly 150 days prior to our birthday with the launch of a...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/" title="Read 150 Years Later&#8230;">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/">150 Years Later&#8230;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Things that turn 150 years old in 2019:</p>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li>The Periodic Table</li>
<li>Professional baseball</li>
<li>UCAN!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>We happen to think UCAN is as innovative and original as our 150 year-old compatriots. But how does one innovatively celebrate such a milestone?</p>
<p>We kicked off our celebrations exactly 150 days prior to our birthday with the launch of a <a href="http://150anniversary.ucanchicago.org/">microsite solely dedicated to our extensive history</a>. In 1869 we were called the &#8220;Uhlich Evangelical Orphan Asylum&#8221; but as the years passed, we thought UCAN had a better ring to it. Along with the microsite, we rolled out  &#8220;UCAN&#8217;s 150 Facts&#8221; campaign where we posted a fact about UCAN&#8217;s history on social media every day until our birthday on March 29. You can check out a collection of them <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/ucanchicagoland/150-facts-about-ucan/">here</a>. </p>
<img class="alignright wp-image-6416 " src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-768x665.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="312" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-768x665.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-268x232.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-320x277.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-966x836.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-720x623.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-290x251.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-369x319.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 360px) 100vw, 360px" />
<p>As fun as it is to highlight UCAN&#8217;s rich history, we also wanted to honor the dedicated employees who continually help move UCAN into the future. Each month, our President/CEO Zack Schrantz presents a select, small group of employees with the 150th Anniversary President&#8217;s Coin to recognize the recipient&#8217;s spirit, service and teamwork they demonstrate to support UCAN’s pursuit of our vision and mission. </p>
<p>We also unveiled our new UCAN 150th anniversary logo along with lamp post banners lining the street outside of our North Lawndale campus and our office on Western Avenue. Coincidentally (or not), the North Lawndale community is also celebrating its 150<sup>th</sup> anniversary this year.</p>
<p>March was a particularly busy month. Our staff members showed their silly side by dressing up for a different theme like Superhero day and Hippie day. The week culminated with our annual Employee Banquet (this year we celebrated in Roaring ‘20s style!). </p>
<img class=" wp-image-6420 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2.png" alt="" width="289" height="231" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2.png 945w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-268x214.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-768x614.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-320x256.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-720x576.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-290x232.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-369x295.png 369w" sizes="(max-width: 289px) 100vw, 289px" />
<p>For our 150th birthday on March 29, we started the day with a party featuring delicious cupcakes, games, music, and perhaps most importantly, celebrating one another and the work we collectively carry out to support the youth, families and communities we serve. </p>
<p>The celebrations did not stop there for later that night, we reached the crescendo of months of work and preparation: the 150th Anniversary Celebration held at the Chicago History Museum. We brought old photos and items, like our accounts ledger from 1890, for guests to peak through, along with a historical yearbook for guests to sign. Everyone was treated to drinks, food and even a performance by the founders of UCAN Voices: Fred Long, Jason Daniels, and Vic Spencer. While the  evening centered on the history of UCAN, our guests understood that we were also celebrating the future.</p>
<img class="wp-image-6423 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717.jpg" alt="" width="469" height="312" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717.jpg 2500w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 469px) 100vw, 469px" />
<p>And we have more to come!</p>
<p>We are looking forward to the expansion of our Healing Garden, Petria&#8217;s Place, located on our Drost Harding Campus in North Lawndale near our youth home. We are installing a brick path that you can also support! To purchase a brick or for more information, <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/150th-anniversary-brick-collection/">click here</a>.</p>
<p>We are looking forward to an event-filled six months and hope you will join us at our 20th annual <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/yla/">Youth Leadership Awards on June 6</a>, help us celebrate the opening of Petria’s Place, contribute to a symposium focused on women’s influence in UCAN’s history, and kick back with us at our youth-centric Peace Fest on June 26.</p>
<p><em>By Carly Hanson</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/">150 Years Later&#8230;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 18:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6380</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode a budding activist in the fight against food insecurity, interviews the Vice President of Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4o1OkmaWSXg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p><strong>How to fight hunger in Chicago and around the world</strong>. In this episode, Jade Wilkins, a budding activist in the fight against food insecurity (and a UCAN participant), interviews Nicole Robinson, Vice President of Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository. They discuss food insecurity, waste, hunger as a product of poverty and inequality, and hope ­– hope arising from a commitment to community.</p>
<p>Other Episodes can be found <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Jade Wilkins: Can you tell me a little bit about your role in the Chicago Food Depository and what you do here?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Nicole Robinson: </strong>I am the Vice President of what we call Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository, and I lead all of our programs, workforce development, and public policy programs. At the food depository, we are committed to ending hunger. We are one of 200 food banks across the country who do this work and we service the greater Chicagoland area within Cook County.</p>
<p>There are about 800,000 people who show up at food pantries, soup kitchens, and shelters across our service area and we help connect them to food, to work. And we help mobilize the public and raise awareness so that we can do something about ending hunger. It&#8217;s all about connecting people to the resources that they need.</p>
<p><strong>JW: That&#8217;s amazing. When I was here volunteering last year, I never would&#8217;ve noticed or imagined that the Greater Chicago Food Depository connects people to these different resources that allow them to get jobs as well as food. </strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you so much for volunteering at the food depository.</p>
<p><strong>JW: Of course.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you for that observation about that work, but Jade, when you think about it, hunger is a symptom of poverty. And when you think about a place like Chicago, some of the key issues we deal with in Chicago are poverty, racial inequity, and violence in our city – and hunger intersects with all of those things. In our work, we take all of that into consideration. If we&#8217;re going to end hunger, it&#8217;s really important for us to think about the economic impact and how we connect people to employment.</p>
<p>One of the programs we have that does that is a culinary training program called Chicago&#8217;s Community Kitchens. It&#8217;s 14 weeks long, and people learn here in our kitchen and in our classroom about the technical skills you need to work in the food industry. Then they get placed in a permanent job. We&#8217;re really proud of that work.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Wow. Why did you to join a nonprofit organization – specifically, the Greater Chicago Food Depository, working on humanitarian issues?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I&#8217;d say two things. One, I&#8217;ve been here about three years and, prior to that, I worked in the food industry. But I’m also a kid of Chicago Southside. I love Chicago, and I&#8217;ve been to other places in the world that deal with food insecurity and malnutrition. Although it has been striking, there are neighborhoods right in my backyard where young people, families, older adults all struggle with getting connected to food.</p>
<p>When I was a kid, I received something called SNAP. It used to be called food stamps and it’s a federal nutrition program where families can go into the grocery store and get the food that they need when they don&#8217;t have enough. So I am very personally aware of what that need is and how important it is to do something about it.</p>
<p>I want things to get better, I want families and individuals, young people to reach their full potential – and good nutrition, healthy food, is a big part of that.</p>
<p><strong>JW: I agree. My family was actually a part of that program at some time. We decided that we wanted to be more independent and not rely on government help by using SNAP or food stamps. That transition did make the situation a little bit worse for a short time. We&#8217;re still struggling, but it&#8217;s really good to make that transition and start developing that individuality. I really do understand that  – and that&#8217;s where my passion for food waste and this issue stems</strong> <strong>from.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I think your passion comes through on this issue for sure.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: </strong><strong>Thank you. Can for-profit organizations be as helpful as nonprofit organizations? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I think that, absolutely, corporations can be helpful in this effort, and we sometimes refer to them as public private partnerships, because nonprofits can&#8217;t do it alone. As an organization, we were actually designed to be an emergency resource for families, not their only source of food.Unfortunately, we&#8217;re  in a state where people come to us more than we actually think they need to, and we would like to make sure they&#8217;re connected to programs like SNAP that can get them the resources that they need.</p>
<p>But corporations are some of our number one partners, because 30 to 40 percent of the food we receive is donated to the food depository. We receive it from grocery stores like Jewel, Osco, Mariano&#8217;s, Aldi.</p>
<p>Starbucks is one of our biggest partners, and they have something called Food Share. They sell food in their stores – salads, sandwiches, fruit, pastries, all sorts of things – and every single day, we have a team of drivers who go to Starbucks stores overnight and they pick up all the food that&#8217;s left over from the previous day. That food goes directly to shelters in the Chicagoland area that are serving people impacted by homelessness.</p>
<p>None of that food goes to waste – and it was their idea to create that program. Starbucks approached us about this partnership.</p>
<p><strong>JW: That is incredible. I would&#8217;ve never imagined.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Most people don&#8217;t know that. Starbucks knew that they were going to sell food in their stores, but what they didn&#8217;t want to see was their unsold food going to waste.</p>
<h2><strong>JW:</strong> <strong>I am curious about one thing. You mentioned that there are grocers that donate food to the Greater Chicago Food Depository. I was wondering, what percentage of that food that would otherwise be wasted in those grocery stores gets donated?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> I don&#8217;t have the exact percentage, Jade, but I&#8217;d say that a good chunk of it is not wasted. Similar to the Starbucks program, what happens is the store managers in those Jewel, Osco, or Mariano&#8217;s stores, at the end of each week, collect the food that&#8217;s not saleable but still good and they save it for us. Then, we have drivers who go to the different stores across the Cook County area and pick up that food. The intent is to get as much as possible.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Right, what do you think happens to the remainder of that food if it is wasted – and why is it wasted?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> We try to get most of it, but what we also need to balance in the equation is that we&#8217;re putting trucks on the road to go get the food. So, for example, if there are only three sandwiches and you send a truck to get them…the cost-benefit analysis doesn’t really work.</p>
<p>But most times, we do get the food. And if we have partners with smaller quantities, those might go to pantry in their neighborhood. The pantry will partner with us and they will actually do the pickup of the food. I think we do our best to reduce the waste as much as possible – but it is about connecting families to the food, right?</p>
<p><strong>JW:  I recall there being an act that allows restaurants, grocers I believe, to be able to donate food.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> The Good Samaritan Act.</p>
<p><strong>JR: Yes!</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> You have done your research, Jade.</p>
<p><strong>JW:</strong><strong> I’ve delved really deep, I’m very passionate about this. I want to find a way to alter the policies that are causing all of this food waste. At my school, students have to pick up a certain amount of fruit or vegetables, and a lot of those students don&#8217;t eat that, so they end up throwing it away. I wanted to find a way other than going to collect it every day, something that&#8217;s more sustainable, something that can be carried on even after I leave Lane Tech.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong>  Did you mobilize students to collect the food that was going to waste?</p>
<p><strong>JW:  I did have a few people who were really interested in that. One student in particular saw me collecting food and they were inspired to do it as well. I&#8217;m unable to collect food during lunch because I have academic obligations. But, this one student goes around and collects the food in my absence, and he does it religiously. It&#8217;s amazing to see that. Honestly, when I saw that for the first time, I was almost moved to tears. Seeing someone else inspired by me inspired me some more.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Right, that&#8217;s what mobilizing the public around an issue is – and you sound like a food justice champion. We need more people like you to do this work. Yes, we&#8217;re partnering with corporations and government, but we still need so many individual people to be involved in this issue.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: One of my main goals in life is to establish my own nonprofit organization, kind of like what we have here at the Greater Chicago Food Depository, and I was wondering, what are the qualifications that you would need, or the qualities that make a successful nonprofit like this? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> There are two pieces to it. Part of it is that hunger has been around for a long time, and the food depository has been around for 40 years. We&#8217;ve been doing good work, but we know that there&#8217;s more to do — and we need to get at the root cause of some of these problems.</p>
<p>I think for someone like you who wants to start a nonprofit, you need to ask yourself, &#8220;What can I do differently?&#8221; And &#8220;What&#8217;s my niche?&#8221; What is the food depository missing, that&#8217;s not being done to serve the community? I think that&#8217;s a big opportunity for you. And part of it is just being curious, curious and listening to people in the community so you get a sense of what they really need so that you&#8217;re giving them the right solutions.</p>
<p><strong>JW: Definitely. I really want to be more involved in the community and I see the community as a family –  but it&#8217;s more like a divided family.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> That is part of the opportunity. How do we bring people together? A lot of times we talk at the food depository about going from transactional relationships to transformational. If we could just make our relationships at home, in the community, and at work transformational, we’d solve all the world&#8217;s problems.</p>
<p>In a world and in a city like Chicago, where there&#8217;s so much wealth, so much opportunity, I want to make sure that the opportunity is spread out, for everybody to reach their full potential, especially in the neighborhoods that today have the least.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: As we draw our interview to a close, I would really like to know, are there any role models in your life that have led you to become the person that you are today, involved in nonprofits such as the Greater Chicago Food Depository that work on issues like food insecurity and food waste?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Sure. Actually, some non-famous people, like teachers in elementary school. Mr. Boyd. And teachers in high school, Carol Gehring.</p>
<p>I had everyday role models. My mom&#8217;s a role model for me. She was a single mom. My grandmother is a role model as well for me because she worked really hard. She was part of something called The Great Migration, and she came from Arkansas for a better life for her and her children.</p>
<p>All of those women inspire me in my life. But then there are so many great women leaders in the city of Chicago. One I think you might be interested in became the head of the World Food Program. She was the first African American woman to lead the World Food Program which works in over 75 countries around the world. She lives right here in Chicago. That’s definitely someone I look up to when I think about this world of anti-hunger work.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Thank you so much for being with us today. It was really wonderful talking to you and learning more about the Greater Chicago Food Depository. </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> It was my pleasure to meet you, Jade. You are phenomenal at what you do, and you&#8217;re smart. Mind if I get a hug?</p>
<p><strong>JW: </strong><strong>Of course!</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you. Thank you for coming to the food depository to do this interview.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opportunity Doesn&#8217;t Knock</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 18:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Employees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6339</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Chase Larkin is a living, breathing example of UCAN's vision and mission: he went from passively attending a youth group to leading it. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/">Opportunity Doesn&#8217;t Knock</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chase Larkin is a living, breathing example of UCAN&#8217;s vision and mission: he went from passively attending a youth group to leading it.  </p>
<p>Chase spent his childhood in Harvey, Illinois, with his mother, grandmother and sister as well as his extended family as neighbors. On weekends, Chase would spend time with his father&#8217;s family on Chicago’s South Side at 93rd Street and Blackstone Avenue.  In both instances, while Chase was surrounded by a community of people who cared about his welfare, there also existed the external influences of gangs and drugs, something both of his parents wanted him to avoid. </p>
<p>So, when in fifth grade, his father relocated to Country Club Hills and invited Chase and his brother to come and live with him.</p>
<p>&#8220;I wanted to live with my dad and my brother. I had never had that before,&#8221; says Chase. &#8220;So we moved out there, but my mind wasn&#8217;t ready for that environment. I brought a lot of 93rd and Blackstone with me and a lot of Harvey mentality to a peaceful neighborhood. I started to get into a little trouble and my grades started to slip and my mom noticed. Fast forward to high school, my mom started working at UCAN.&#8221;<img class="alignright wp-image-6365 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-268x402.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="402" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-268x402.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-768x1152.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-320x480.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-966x1449.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-720x1080.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-290x435.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-369x554.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></p>
<p>In 2006, Chase&#8217;s mother, Michael Ann Wiley, joined UCAN. She met Fred Long, the current Vice President of Development, who had grown up in UCAN programming. Fred told Michael Ann about a male mentoring program called Project Visible Man (PVM), and she immediately knew Chase should be in it.</p>
<p>She picked him up every Wednesday after school and drove him across the city to the group. At 16, it was a new experience for Chase, and it took him six months for him to begin to open up.</p>
<p>&#8220;At that time I just wasn&#8217;t ready to hear it. I was like, ‘I&#8217;m fine doing exactly what I&#8217;m doing.’ But as time passed people really just started being more invested in my life. I would see Fred on non-PVM days and he would ask me how I&#8217;m doing, and Claude [Robinson, Executive Vice President of External Affairs &amp; Diversity] would too.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jason Daniels, a Youth Development Coach at UCAN, would also help get Chase more engaged in the group. It didn&#8217;t take long before Chase was fully invested. Soon after, Claude had Chase began to go on exposure outings via the Striving To Achieve Realistic Success (STARs) program. </p>
<p>By 18, Chase was facilitating PVM. By 19, he was officially a UCAN employee as a Youth Development Coach. </p>
<p>&#8220;It brought out new qualities and skills that I didn&#8217;t know I had,&#8221; he says of leading PVM. For most of his life, he thought he wanted to be a lawyer, but after being in PVM and taking a few college courses in the field, he learned it wasn&#8217;t the right fit. He realized, however, he would have come to that conclusion sooner had he taken the opportunity of a summer internship at a law office during high school.</p>
<p>&#8220;If I would have done that internship, I probably would have figured it out before I took these classes. I was just like, ‘I need to be more intentional about taking opportunities even if they may not sound fun or immediately beneficial, I need to start thinking more long term.’&#8221;</p>
<p>There was one moment that made Chase realize this was what he truly wanted to do. It was at &#8220;Learn and Earn,&#8221; a program in which high school youth attended an event to learn reading, writing, arithmetic and life skills.</p>
<p>&#8220;A youth got mad at a young lady and he punched a hole in the wall. I remember sitting down and having a very good conversation about life in general and it had very little to do with him punching the wall, but it had to do with managing emotions and being productive. We had a very good talk and when he walked away, I could tell during the rest of the program, he would be very intentional about not getting in trouble. It was that one conversation that made all the difference, and it wasn&#8217;t even about punching the wall. We just talked.&#8221;</p>
<p>After that, Chase knew he was on the right path. </p>
<p>&#8220;This is my passion. I really enjoy gathering as much information as possible and learn, and I really enjoy spreading that knowledge and see it be beneficial to someone else. My belief is that all the information that I get is not always for me. It&#8217;s selfish of me to hold on to that and not spread it along. I think about the knowledge that I have now, that I didn&#8217;t have when I at 16 and 15, it would be selfish of me to not reach out to the 13 year old and say, “Listen, this is something you might need.’&#8221;</p>
<p>After 11 years as a UCAN employee, Chase reflects on what his career has taught him.</p>
<p>&#8220;UCAN opened my eyes to different opportunities. One thing I learned is that opportunity doesn&#8217;t knock. We think opportunity comes to us, that we either miss it or we don&#8217;t take it, but the truth is opportunities are around us all the time. The reason why we don&#8217;t acknowledge them is because we are not prepared to see them as opportunities, so I think UCAN has opened my eyes to be more prepared to spot opportunities, even when those opportunities aren&#8217;t for myself.&#8221;</p>
<p>This year, Chase was honored with a UCAN President&#8217;s Coin to recognize his spirit, service and teamwork.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/">Opportunity Doesn&#8217;t Knock</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>UCAN Celebrates Women</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 18:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Employees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6343</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>UCAN practices and celebrates diversity, equity and inclusion year round, and in honor of International Women's History Month held two women-centric events for all genders.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/">UCAN Celebrates Women</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UCAN practices and celebrates diversity, equity and inclusion year round, and in honor of International Women&#8217;s History Month held two women-centric events for all genders.</p>
<p>To kick off the month, the Diversity, Equity and Inclusion Committee, along with Sisterhood 180, held the second annual Black Women&#8217;s Leadership Brunch on March 27, that brought together a panel of inspiring, successful black female professionals who are leaders within the their respective industry. The panel comprised five women: Rhonda Haynes of the National Association for Urban Debate Leagues, Deborah Olivia Farmer of Brown Farmer Media Group, Inc., Tracie D. Hall of The Joyce Foundation, Cristel Turner of U.S. Cellular, and former news anchor Robin Robinson, now the Director of Community Affairs at the Chicago Police Department.</p>
<img class=" wp-image-6360 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1.png" alt="" width="380" height="283" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1.png 668w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1-268x200.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1-320x239.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1-290x216.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1-369x275.png 369w" sizes="(max-width: 380px) 100vw, 380px" />
<p>The discussion focused on the intersection of gender and race, and the unique obstacles it can create in your personal and professional lives.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have nothing to gain by staying small,&#8221; said Tracie Hall. &#8220;I always heard friends talking about making more opportunities for black girls to be queens and princess. I always wanted to be the wizard! I wanted to do magic and have power.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Anyone can be a leader,&#8221; added Cristel Turner.</p>
<p>The next event on International Women&#8217;s Day, March 8, was Women &amp; Co&#8217;s &#8220;Celebrating (extra)Ordinary Women.&#8221; Participants explored women&#8217;s history, the history of women at UCAN, and spent an hour &#8220;speed mentoring.&#8221; They learned how to empower, collaborate and encourage girls and women in our lives (including ourselves) to embrace the strength and confidence within them/us.</p>
<p><img class=" wp-image-6368 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice.jpg" alt="" width="341" height="275" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice.jpg 512w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice-268x216.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice-320x258.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice-290x234.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice-369x298.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 341px) 100vw, 341px" />The event concluded with an interactive art piece dedicated to extraordinary women. The keynote speaker was Laura Angelucci, UCAN’s Vice President of Administration, and she went through the history of feminism and intersectionality within the movement. Participants were also treated to &#8220;A Brief History of Women at UCAN,&#8221; which in relation to UCAN&#8217;s full history was anything but brief. </p>
<p>&#8220;(extra)Ordinary Women highlighted a diverse array of talents among women inside and outside of UCAN,” says Rebecca Brown, Development Coordinator at UCAN. “It offered a space for people to connect with each other while learning about the true meaning of feminism &#8211; the belief that men and women should have equal rights and opportunities.&#8221;</p>
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6367" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404.jpg" alt="" width="6000" height="4000" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404.jpg 6000w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 6000px) 100vw, 6000px" />
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/">UCAN Celebrates Women</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 5</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 20:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6309</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest. For our fifth interview, Caleb Hunter, a former UCAN participant and now a college sophomore studying Cybersecurity, met with Robert Matles, a technologist and Managing Director for J.P. Morgan Chase,...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/" title="Read Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 5">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 5</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p>For our fifth interview, Caleb Hunter, a former UCAN participant and now a college sophomore studying Cybersecurity, met with Robert Matles, a technologist and Managing Director for J.P. Morgan Chase, the global financial firm, who helps lead over 1800 technology professionals housed in seven very un-bank-like floors of the firm’s downtown Chicago office. They discussed what it takes to get into technology, what firms are looking for in new hires, and even whether or not Chicago will be the next Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>Find other episodes <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6Ol4GuVdBHA" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe> </p>
<h2><strong>Caleb Hunter:</strong>  Mr. Matles, would you please introduce yourself?</h2>
<p><strong>Robert Matles:</strong>  First of all, I want to thank you for the opportunity to spend some time with you today. My name is Rob Matles, and I&#8217;m a managing director at J.P. Morgan Chase. I&#8217;m a technologist and I work on and build systems that move ten percent of the world&#8217;s money every day.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong> What are the best qualities of your job?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> I&#8217;ll tell you that for me, the best thing is to work with some fantastic people. I can&#8217;t stress how incredible the amount of energy, the amount of passion, the amount of curiosity, and the amount of intellect is here.</p>
<p>The other thing that I really like about this job is that you can make a difference. So, what we work on you can actually see value in it. I&#8217;ll give you an example. Last year, I was working on a project where we reduced the time it takes to open accounts for big companies, from 12 days to less than two hours. So, think of the value of that to companies who are now able to open accounts that quickly and start doing business with us. So, you can really  see the positive impact you have on the economy.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong> What are the biggest challenge that come with being the Managing Director of IT?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> I would say there&#8217;s two really big challenges. One is, things happen so fast in today&#8217;s world. Software, startups, FinTechs, Microsoft, the Googles, the Amazons of the world – they&#8217;re all moving at warp speed. Our challenge is not just to work that fast and deliver things quickly and be innovative, it&#8217;s also that we have to make sure that our clients&#8217; data is private. And every day, someone comes in and tries to figure out how to break into our systems and offices. So, those two challenges,  going really fast while staying ahead of the bad guys and keeping everything secure, is really big for us.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong> What can companies like J.P. Morgan Chase offer my generation in terms of career opportunities?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> So, the big secret is J.P. Morgan has 50,000 technologists that work for them. And, we do everything that you can think about when you think about IT or technology. So, things that we can offer are: we have cybersecurity jobs, we have software engineering jobs, we have people who like to work on infrastructure, we have testing jobs, people who run programs, along with machine learning and data science activities.  We offer a vast array of opportunities in technology.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong> Where would you ask people in my generation to start in order to learn about cybersecurity, computer science and programming, so they can launch themselves into the rapidly advancing technology of today’s world?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> First of all, I think the closest thing that we have to superheroes today are people who are in technology. The reason I say that is because you have the ability from a keyboard to change the world, just with the software you write and the ability to put something in the cloud and touch so many people. There aren’t many things out there that I can think of that let you change the world like that.</p>
<p>Think of Netflix, think of Google, they all started in a garage, on a computer – and look what they&#8217;ve done. So, what I say to young folks is that the first thing is make sure you understand the principles, the science behind computer or software engineering so that you have a base grounding.</p>
<p>But once you have that, I recommend that you go with your passion – and I wouldn&#8217;t start and stay in one silo. We look for people who are well-rounded, so start with cyber, start with programming, but don&#8217;t stay there. Move around. Get well-rounded, because what we see is that the folks who excel are passionate, they love coming to work, and they do more than one thing. So that&#8217;s what I would tell folks looking to come into the field of technology.</p>
<p>And you can&#8217;t think of your career in more than five-year chunks. So, if you think of your first two years, if you can do three, four different things, that’ll get you grounded in a way that you can pivot and go whichever direction that you’re passionate about.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  As a Managing Director, what do you at look for in young people who want to work for J.P. Morgan Chase in technology?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> We look for a few things. One, we look for someone with software engineering or a computer science background. We look for people who are curious, who like to learn new things. We look for people who are very good at solving problems, who have great critical thinking skills, are self-starters, who communicate well and ask questions.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  Can you give a description of your interview process?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong>  We have a couple of different types of interviews. We interview people with experience and then we interview folks who are coming out of college who we call new hires.</p>
<p>For the new hires, we start out with some general screening interviews where we get to know you. We get to know what you are interested in, what you are passionate about. If we think that you are a good fit culturally, we&#8217;ll bring you in and you get to talk to three, four, sometimes five people about your experiences, and we look for some of those traits that I was talking about.</p>
<p>We want to make sure that you&#8217;re a self-starter. We want to make sure that you can solve problems and enjoy solving problems, and we want to make sure you&#8217;re curious because we have to come in everyday and want to learn something. People are very successful if they&#8217;re driven by curiosity and driven by themselves to push through problems.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  Is Chase always looking to diversify it’s work environment with employees and managers who are dedicated to diversity?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> Yes. Inclusion and diversity are extremely important to me. Coming from a military background, it&#8217;s second nature to me, but we actually have thirty three percent woman who work in technology in Chicago. The average in the industry is well below ten percent.</p>
<p>From an ethnicity perspective, we have resource groups. We have a group called Bold, which is focused on black Americans. We have a group that&#8217;s called Aspire, focused on Asians. We have a group of military veterans…and those are just a few examples of how we look for ways to build community and diversity.</p>
<p>In my experience – and I&#8217;ve been doing this for, let&#8217;s just call it twenty-five plus years – is that the more diverse your team is, the better performing they are. That goes back to a couple of things. One is that people see things from different viewpoints, if they come from different walks of life. And two is, you get diversity of thought. People don&#8217;t all think the same, and the last thing that we want to do is to hire fifty Rob Matleses because then we wouldn&#8217;t have people with strength in different areas. We think we can diversify more and it&#8217;s a big focus.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  One final question. Do you believe Chicago will become the next Silicon Valley?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong>  First of all, I would say that we&#8217;re never going to be Silicon Valley. Which is fine, which is fantastically fine, it&#8217;s great, because guess what? We&#8217;re Chicago, we&#8217;re unique in the fact that we are the center point for the intersection for all kinds of industries, all kinds of people, and not in the physical world only but also in the digital world.</p>
<p>Every day, a new startup starts in Chicago. We have over 100,000 jobs in this area for technology. And if you look at the companies here like J.P. Morgan Chase, we have fantastic opportunities to not only drive business, but drive our economy and communities and really give back. So, I&#8217;m very, very optimistic and bullish on Chicago becoming a great tech hub for the 21st century.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Matles, for giving us your time today. It&#8217;s been a pleasure.</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> My pleasure, Caleb. I enjoyed the time with you, and I look forward to seeing some great things in the IT industry in the future.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 5</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 19:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6280</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>A doctor. An actor. A businessman. A reporter. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/">Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A doctor. An actor. A businessman. A reporter. </p>
<p>Four unique aspirations of four unique youth.</p>
<p>UCAN supporter and marketing consultant, Chuck Kent, had an idea to help make those dreams a reality: give youth the opportunity to have a discussion with a professional who works in the field the youth aspires to develop a career. The idea grew into a series of videos in which UCAN youth interview notable Chicago professionals about their respective careers and industry.</p>
<p>These conversations not only explore how one gets into such work, but why and how that career is valuable to the city and its people. It’s all part of our conviction at UCAN that today’s youth, even when faced with trauma, can become tomorrow’s leaders.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more episodes!</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6033 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 1</a></h1>
<p><em>The interviewer for our inaugural episode is Ariyan Moore, currently a marketing student, who spoke with </em><em>John </em><em>Starkey</em><em>, Global Brand Leader for Dove and Galaxy chocolates at </em><em>Mars</em><em>. </em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6123 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 2</a></h1>
<p><em>In our second episode, Briana Owens, an aspiring broadcaster and currently a student at Ithaca College interviews Brandis Griffith-Friedman, a correspondent and segment host for Chicago Tonight on WTTW, Chicago’s public television station.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/">here</a>. </p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6118 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 3</a></h1>
<p><em>In the third episode, Ebonie Henderson, an aspiring actress, visits the Goodman Theater to interview Henry Godinez, Resident Artistic Associate and a professor at Northwestern University.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/">here</a>. </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-6189 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-268x144.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="144" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-268x144.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-768x412.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-320x172.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-966x518.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-720x386.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-290x156.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-369x198.jpg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></a><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">Watch Episode 4</a></h1>
<p><em>In the fourth episode, Maya Hunter, a UCAN participant who aspires to be a physician, interviews Dr. Perpetua Goodall, an Associate Professor of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology at the University of Chicago.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/">Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6279</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>"Today we are celebrating Dr. King while also coming out to support our community,” said Nadine Toussaint, a student at UIC. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/">Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the growing Civil Rights Movement incited detractors in 1959, many faith leaders in Chicago feared backlash and refused to allow Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. to preach to their congregations. Reverend James Marcellus Stone, then pastor of Stone Temple Baptist Church, welcomed Dr. King to preach, knowing that a message of justice and love should be welcomed in his church.</p>
<p>On January 26 of 1966, one year after declaring Chicago the epicenter of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference&#8217;s civil rights efforts in the north, Dr. King and his wife Coretta moved to a quaint apartment on the West Side of the city in North Lawndale, across the street from the Stone Temple Baptist Church. Stone Temple would go on to become Dr. King’s &#8220;action center&#8221; for the Civil Rights Movement. Though Dr. King&#8217;s apartment is gone, Stone Temple continues to be a pillar in North Lawndale, the home of UCAN’s headquarters.</p>
<img class="alignright wp-image-6284 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-268x357.jpeg" alt="" width="268" height="357" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-268x357.jpeg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-768x1024.jpeg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-320x427.jpeg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-966x1288.jpeg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-720x960.jpeg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-290x387.jpeg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-369x492.jpeg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180.jpeg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
<p>For the annual ‘MLK Day of Service,’ observed on Dr. King’s  birthday, the University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC) Student Leadership and Civic Engagement&#8217;s office reached out to UCAN ready to give back to their community. </p>
<p>&#8220;We had the opportunity to engage UIC students in North Lawndale and felt that our community needed the support more than us,We build up and support youth who’ve suffered trauma,&#8221; says Andrea Lee, Manager of External Affairs Manager at UCAN. &#8220;We work with youth themselves, their families, and their community – like with this project. We had the chance to lead this service project to support pillar in our community of North Lawndale that continues to be an ‘action center’ – of spirituality and community connectedness. In addition to supporting the youth through our programs, we recognize that supporting other community institutions is another critical way to build strong youth and families.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fifty students from UIC arrived at Stone Temple Baptist Church on January 21<sup>st</sup> ready to paint, organize, deep clean, and repair floors.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today we are celebrating Dr. King while also coming out to support our community,” said Nadine Toussaint, a student at UIC. </p>
<p>Though many people across the country participate in the MLK Day of Service, the UIC students’ day of service was unique in that they gave back to the same community that Dr. King embraced as his own decades before.</p>
<p>“It was really great because some of the community members of the church were hanging out to see what we were doing and encouraging us and thanking us for being there,&#8221; says Samantha Lagestee, another UIC student.</p>
<p>By the end of the day, the volunteers had painted two large conference rooms, washed walls in high-traffic hallways, organized the storage room and deep-cleaned the storage area.</p>
<p>“I am grateful for UCAN. I am grateful for the students that came from UIC,&#8221; says Pastor Reshorna Fitzpatrick of Stone Temple. &#8220;I’m just excited today, it’s just a beautiful project taking place. I’m sure if Dr. King was alive he’d be happy to see all of us coming together in one place having a united front.”</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=369657973867386">Check out UIC&#8217;s video recapping their Day of Service!</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/">Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mentees to Mentors</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 15:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Employees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6181</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>At the very core of UCAN is youth development. It’s the underlying constant within each program, and of the tools used to support their development, mentoring remains one of the strongest and most effective. “Mentor” can mean someone who you look up to or someone you aspire to be. It can be someone who pushes...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/" title="Read Mentees to Mentors">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/">Mentees to Mentors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the very core of UCAN is youth development. It’s the underlying constant within each program, and of the tools used to support their development, mentoring remains one of the strongest and most effective.</p>
<p>“Mentor” can mean someone who you look up to or someone you aspire to be. It can be someone who pushes you or someone who supports you whether a family member or a colleague. </p>
<p>But for two youth at UCAN, mentor means someone who has changed their lives.</p>
<p>Seantayvia Byrd came to UCAN two years ago through the Violence Intervention and Prevention Services program. Now she is a senior in high school and looking forward to her future with the support of her Youth Development Coach Nadia Hill. </p>
<p>“I know that she cares &#8211; for real,” says Seantayvia of Nadia.</p>
<p>As Seantayvia navigates her last year of school, she’s looked to Nadia for help in making decisions about her future. Though she hasn’t applied to college yet, she plans to attend, and when the time comes, Nadia will be there to assist her in the application process and beyond. Her goal: become a psychologist.</p>
<p>Yasmine Kirkwood, another UCAN youth, shares Seantayvia’s enthusiasm for psychology.  She cites her therapist as her mentor.</p>
<p>“I just love her,” Yasmine says. “She gave me more confidence; she helped me come out of my shell. She’s my inspiration. I don’t know what I’d do without her.”</p>
<p>Because of the support and guidance Yasmine received from her therapist after her father died, she knew this is what she&#8217;s meant to do: help people like her. &#8220;Making other people feel good, it helps me.&#8221;</p>
<p>“It’s good to have a person like that outside of your family,” Seantayvia adds.</p>
<p>Nadia Hill is herself a mentee having spent most of her life in North Lawndale. From a young age, she was active in after school programs such as the Boys and Girls Club. </p>
<p>&#8220;[My mother] was very intentional,” she says, “to make sure I was very involved with community,&#8221; and that connection is a reason she became a youth development coach.</p>
<p>&#8220;It doesn&#8217;t matter who I work with,&#8221; says Nadia. &#8220;I want them to see that they can be self-sufficient.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/">Mentees to Mentors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
