<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Volunteers &#8211; UCAN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/category/personal-stories/volunteers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org</link>
	<description>Youth who have suffered trauma can become our future leaders</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 20:44:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Chance Connections to Deepened Relationships</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 18:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6434</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>By Andrea Lee, MPA, Manager of External Affairs April was National Volunteer Month, which to me, is a month of possibilities: possible connections, possible relationships, possible awakenings to one’s own city. I am dedicated to connecting community members to UCAN’s programs and people in meaningful ways. Through these relationships across geography, wealth, age, race, and...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/" title="Read Chance Connections to Deepened Relationships">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/">Chance Connections to Deepened Relationships</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>By Andrea Lee, MPA, Manager of External Affairs</em></p>
<p>April was National Volunteer Month, which to me, is a month of possibilities: possible connections, possible relationships, possible awakenings to one’s own city.</p>
<p>I am dedicated to connecting community members to UCAN’s programs and people in meaningful ways. Through these relationships across geography, wealth, age, race, and everything else, we build empathy and see each other’s humanity beyond our facades.</p>
<p>Case in point: A chance connection last fall has led to a supportive bond between a community member and a young person living in UCAN’s Diermeier Therapeutic Youth Home. I happened to sit beside a woman at the North Lawndale Community Coordinating Council’s (NLCCC) meeting to launch their Quality of Life plan, to which UCAN is a key contributor. She mentioned she wanted to get involved in North Lawndale, so I learned that her name is Kenya Harris and we setup an appointment to discuss mentorship at UCAN. Today, she is the mentor to a 13 year-old who lives at the Therapeutic Youth Home and who has no other community supports or family. When I asked Kenya what it feels like to be a mentor, she responded:</p>
<p>“Being a mentor makes me feel good and is truly a blessing.  To be part of a support system to a child in need is very rewarding.  I feel lack of support is the primary reason many people have difficult times in their lives.  For me, being a mentor is about letting my mentee know that she has my support and I care.”</p>
<p>The relationship can get complex, and the mentee sometimes asks for more than a mentor can give. I asked Kenya what was challenging about being a mentor, and she wrote:</p>
<p>“I never want her to feel like if I’m unable to do something it’s due to lack of care.  So, I’m currently in the stage of creating healthy boundaries through communication so that she knows I care and if it’s something with in my powers to do, I will.” <img class="size-medium wp-image-6438 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-268x201.jpeg" alt="" width="268" height="201" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-268x201.jpeg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-768x576.jpeg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-320x240.jpeg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-966x725.jpeg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-720x540.jpeg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-290x218.jpeg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/use-this-one-2-369x277.jpeg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></p>
<p>Sometimes, it’s a chance connection with a large institution, like the University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC). On a whim, UCAN applied to receive products made by students during “Make Mondays Matter,” a few hours oncampus when volunteers assemble goods for distribution. This led to 40 students supporting one of UCAN’s close partners, Stone Temple Baptist Church, during UIC’s MLK Day of Service, and then painting walls and completing a variety of projects at UCAN Academy  Grand during UIC’s Day of Service on April 13. Kennedy Hayes, a UIC graduate student in public administration, took some time recently to reflect on what UIC’s engagement with UCAN has meant to their students.</p>
<p>“Students have been able to see all of the ways that they can get involved so close to campus. UCAN covers so many projects that students can see and work with the issues that are happening in their own community.”</p>
<p>Kennedy also considered what it meant to work with each other, as we are geographically close but different in aims.</p>
<p>“It is vital for UIC to be more than a stand-alone university in the middle of Chicago. Integration with the surrounding community is so important for a thriving and successful population.”</p>
<p>Wrapping up National Volunteer Month is bittersweet. While the volume of projects would be difficult to maintain over the year, these examples highlight volunteerism’s ability to bring individuals and institutions together toward shared goals and a vision for a more cohesive society.</p>
<p><em>Check out our events during National Volunteer Month on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/UCANchicago">@UCANchicago</a>. </em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/">Chance Connections to Deepened Relationships</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chance-connections-to-deepened-relationships/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6279</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>"Today we are celebrating Dr. King while also coming out to support our community,” said Nadine Toussaint, a student at UIC. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/">Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the growing Civil Rights Movement incited detractors in 1959, many faith leaders in Chicago feared backlash and refused to allow Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. to preach to their congregations. Reverend James Marcellus Stone, then pastor of Stone Temple Baptist Church, welcomed Dr. King to preach, knowing that a message of justice and love should be welcomed in his church.</p>
<p>On January 26 of 1966, one year after declaring Chicago the epicenter of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference&#8217;s civil rights efforts in the north, Dr. King and his wife Coretta moved to a quaint apartment on the West Side of the city in North Lawndale, across the street from the Stone Temple Baptist Church. Stone Temple would go on to become Dr. King’s &#8220;action center&#8221; for the Civil Rights Movement. Though Dr. King&#8217;s apartment is gone, Stone Temple continues to be a pillar in North Lawndale, the home of UCAN’s headquarters.</p>
<img class="alignright wp-image-6284 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-268x357.jpeg" alt="" width="268" height="357" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-268x357.jpeg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-768x1024.jpeg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-320x427.jpeg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-966x1288.jpeg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-720x960.jpeg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-290x387.jpeg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-369x492.jpeg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180.jpeg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
<p>For the annual ‘MLK Day of Service,’ observed on Dr. King’s  birthday, the University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC) Student Leadership and Civic Engagement&#8217;s office reached out to UCAN ready to give back to their community. </p>
<p>&#8220;We had the opportunity to engage UIC students in North Lawndale and felt that our community needed the support more than us,We build up and support youth who’ve suffered trauma,&#8221; says Andrea Lee, Manager of External Affairs Manager at UCAN. &#8220;We work with youth themselves, their families, and their community – like with this project. We had the chance to lead this service project to support pillar in our community of North Lawndale that continues to be an ‘action center’ – of spirituality and community connectedness. In addition to supporting the youth through our programs, we recognize that supporting other community institutions is another critical way to build strong youth and families.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fifty students from UIC arrived at Stone Temple Baptist Church on January 21<sup>st</sup> ready to paint, organize, deep clean, and repair floors.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today we are celebrating Dr. King while also coming out to support our community,” said Nadine Toussaint, a student at UIC. </p>
<p>Though many people across the country participate in the MLK Day of Service, the UIC students’ day of service was unique in that they gave back to the same community that Dr. King embraced as his own decades before.</p>
<p>“It was really great because some of the community members of the church were hanging out to see what we were doing and encouraging us and thanking us for being there,&#8221; says Samantha Lagestee, another UIC student.</p>
<p>By the end of the day, the volunteers had painted two large conference rooms, washed walls in high-traffic hallways, organized the storage room and deep-cleaned the storage area.</p>
<p>“I am grateful for UCAN. I am grateful for the students that came from UIC,&#8221; says Pastor Reshorna Fitzpatrick of Stone Temple. &#8220;I’m just excited today, it’s just a beautiful project taking place. I’m sure if Dr. King was alive he’d be happy to see all of us coming together in one place having a united front.”</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=369657973867386">Check out UIC&#8217;s video recapping their Day of Service!</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/">Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Year of the Volunteer</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 21:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6080</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>We all know time can pass by us in a blur. That is why we give special praise to those who slow down, take some time to reflect, and give a little bit of their most cherished resource… their time.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/">The Year of the Volunteer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all know time can pass by us in a blur. That is why we give special praise to those who slow down, take some time to reflect, and give a little bit of their most cherished resource… their time.</p>
<p>#TwitterForGood Day happens twice a year around the globe.  This year Twitter conducted over 76 service projects across 16 offices around the world. In Chicago a group of 20 “Tweeps” helped UCAN spruce up their conference rooms by painting Chicago neighborhood murals.</p>
<img class="wp-image-6079 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954.jpg" alt="" width="272" height="363" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954.jpg 2448w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-268x357.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-768x1024.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-320x427.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-966x1288.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-720x960.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-290x387.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-369x492.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 272px) 100vw, 272px" />
<p>Twitter was built to foster communication on a global scale because they believe the open exchange of information can be a compelling force for good in the world.  The mission for corporate philanthropy at Twitter is to reflect and augment the positive power of their platform through civic engagement, employee volunteerism, charitable contributions, and in-kind donations.  In these ways, their company can foster greater understanding, equality and opportunities available in cities where they operate. </p>
<p>One of the volunteers from Twitter, Michelle Tomblin, reflected on her experience, “I personally loved getting a better feel for the great work that UCAN does for the Chicago community.  The staff at UCAN really made sure to educate Twitter Chicago on the many programs that UCAN offers including Project Visible Man, crisis prevention, therapy, etc.  I left there eager to find more opportunities where @TwitterChicago and UCAN can partner together in the near future in order to make an impact with the youth of Chicago!”</p>
<p>We’d like to give a virtual high five and pat on the back to our friends at Twitter as well as several other stellar groups of volunteers who went out of their way to give back where UCAN needed them most this year.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Allstate</strong> – As part of an annual conference, 25 senior leaders from Allstate, including UCAN Governing Board Member Mario Rizzo, painted the gym at UCAN Academy Grand, our therapeutic day school in Humboldt Park.
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-6077 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></li>
<li><strong>Aramark </strong>– In partnership with City Year, over 100 volunteers showed the value of a little elbow grease and beautified UCAN’s outdoor space with new benches, sports equipment and a mural during Aramark Building Community (ABC) Day. 
</li>
<li><strong>Kiser Group and Northern Trust</strong> – Donated treat bags and passed out candy to over 300 children trick or treating on Halloween in North Lawndale.
</li>
<li><strong>Delta Kappa Delta</strong> –The ladies of Delta Kappa Delta showed our staff their work is important by rejuvenating our Western Avenue office walls with fresh coats of paint.
</li>
<li><strong>US Bank – </strong>Four prominent leaders at US Bank took time to host a leadership conference for UCAN staff members.
</li>
<li><strong>4 Star Talent – </strong>Our new neighbors on the West Side collected over 300 gifts and toys to brighten the holidays for our youth and families this season. 
<img class="wp-image-6090 size-medium alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-320x214.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-369x246.jpg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
</li>
<li><strong>Catherine Cook School</strong> – These thoughtful students proved knowledge is power by organizing a book drive spearheaded by UCAN Governing Board Vice Chairperson Susan McNally Wilde.</li>
<li><strong>Sigma Gamma Rho Sorority</strong> – Members of the Delta Sigma alumnae chapter collected over 300 pairs of new shoes for youth in UCAN&#8217;s Violence Intervention and Prevention Program.</li>
</ol>
<p>There is always more to do and we have the chance to make 2019’s volunteer initiatives bigger and more impactful! If your company, fraternity, social group or school wants to strengthen our Chicago community through volunteerism, please contact Andrea Lee at <a href="mailto:andrea.lee@ucanchicago.org">Andrea.Lee@UCANChicago.org</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/">The Year of the Volunteer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
