<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; UCAN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org</link>
	<description>Youth who have suffered trauma can become our future leaders</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 19:10:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 7</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 16:32:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6481</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest. Finance, the future of Chicago, and how young people from any background can find a career. In this episode of our interview series, Yusuf Aljabri, a UCAN participant and aspiring...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/" title="Read Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 7">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 7</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/L9Tq2lK8ciE" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p><strong>Finance, the future of Chicago, and how young people from any background can find a career.</strong> In this episode of our interview series, Yusuf Aljabri, a UCAN participant and aspiring finance professional, sits down with Kourtney Gibson, President of Loop Capital Markets and a regular commentator on CNBC, to explore how she made it to a leading position in the financial industry, what advice she has for young people interested in entering the field, and why she feels the financial industry is important to the future of Chicago.</p>
<p>Other Episodes can be found <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Yusuf Aljabri:  Ms. Gibson, would you please introduce yourself and tell us a little bit more about Loop Capital Markets and what it is that you do here.</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Kourtney Gibson:</strong>  I&#8217;m Kourtney Gibson, President of Loop Capital Markets. We’re one of the largest privately held investment banks in the country and the largest minority owned investment banking firm. What we do here at Loop Capital is underwrite on behalf of institutions, ranging from public institutions like the city of Chicago and Chicago Public schools through corporations like the Exelons of the world.</p>
<p>We also trade stocks and bonds in the secondary market on behalf of institutional investors across the country, ranging in size from the BlackRocks of the world (which is the largest asset manager on the planet) all the way through smaller asset management firms you may have never even heard of before. We are an investment bank and brokerage firm.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:  So, did you always plan to go into finance? And if not, what changed your mind?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong>  Absolutely not! I was going to be a bilingual pediatrician. Then I went to undergrad at the University of Miami and I got into the business school – I tested in, and I said, “Well, this business thing could be interesting.”</p>
<p>I was fortunate enough to have interned here at Loop Capital when I was 16 years old, so I had an introduction to business and finance – but I still was going to be a doctor initially. Then, after taking some business courses, and continuing to intern here as well as at Morgan Stanley in New York, I decided this might be the path I want to pursue. So, I decided to stick with finance, majoring in international finance and marketing, with a minor in business law (you always have to know the legal side of things) and I have been at Loop Capital ever since.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>Cool, so what kind of jobs are there at Loop Capital?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> Take your pick. When you think about an investment bank there are a lot of things that make it go, from the technology and working in IT to the accounting and finance functions that we have here, through marketing, through creative writing…there are a lot of things you can do here – and that&#8217;s not even on the business side yet.</p>
<p>On the business side there are a number of opportunities. At the entry level, generally speaking, is our analyst program, and from the analyst level you go into being an associate, then a VP, SVP, Managing Director…As a matter of fact, if you wanted to become CEO here one day the door is open for anyone that has the will, the aptitude and the integrity to get the job done.</p>
<p>There are a number of things you can do here at the firm also from a specific perspective. We have bankers, we have traders, we have sales people on the business side, and on the administrative side is human resources, accounting, legal, IT, marketing, you name it.</p>
<h2><strong>YA: So, what should someone like me who aspires to be into business and finance do right now as they prepare for their future careers?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KA:</strong> The number one thing you start with – and I don&#8217;t care if you want to be the CEO of a company or you want to go do something totally outside of finance – the number one thing is your education. If you can get the grades right that sets the stage to opening the door for you to anything that you want.</p>
<p>In addition to that education you need integrity. People have to know and believe that you are a person of your word and that you do the right thing. Don&#8217;t ever sacrifice that for anything; everything else will follow suit, but you have to have integrity.</p>
<p>And you have to work hard. So, as you’re working hard, whether that is at school or whether that is in after school programs, doing the best, being the best will help to shape your future (in my humble opinion), to be able to open the door for you on the business side of things.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:  What was your motivation throughout your college years,  and how did that get you to where you are today in terms of your career?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong>  What motivates me? I am a woman of faith and family. I am very strong in my faith and I love my family, and I feel like I need to be successful in order to make sure that I can make my family successful and generations to come. That motivates me. <br />I want to be the best that I can be for – and it sounds really clichéd – but for the world, ultimately. If I can do my little part in this little thing called life, hopefully I can impact this world in a positive way.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>I&#8217;ve seen that you are a regular guest on CNBC. How is that, being the face of Loop Capital Markets? Is there any pressure when you go on that show and have to represent the company?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> There&#8217;s tons of pressure!  Not only am I feeling like I represent the company, but there are a lot more weights that I feel are on my back at any given point in time. And so, I&#8217;m nervous every time I go on – but that nervousness actually forces me to prepare.</p>
<p>When you think about the fact that there are young girls and young boys that are looking on that screen and I may be the only person of color or the only woman that&#8217;s a person of color that they see that entire day on that network. It&#8217;s important to me that I make sure they understand that they can do this, too – that I am up there doing just as much and saying and being as on top of it as all the other gentleman that are sitting around me at those tables.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong> <strong>How do you see the financial industry being important to Chicago and the future?</strong></h2>
<p>KA: I think the financial services industry is a part of the fabric of this community.  Aside from the money that moves within a lot of these institutions, the financial institutions have an obligation and an ability – and candidly they have been stepping up to the plate  – around actually working with communities.</p>
<p>Think about a lot of the not-for-profits that are here in the city…think about the different entities that help and give back, whether that be through internships, donations, different programs. Many of those not-for-profit boards consist of people that come from the financial services industry, from the Jim Reynolds of the world to the John Rogers of the world to a myriad of other CEOs that are across this city. They really do get behind making Chicago the epicenter of financial services – and making sure that everyone is participating in that economic development.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>Do you think it is important to find minority youth that are interested in finance, and try to teach them things they may not be exposed to coming from the places that they do?</strong></h2>
<p>KG: Definitely, and many of the institutions across the city have internship programs. I sit on the board of the Chicago Scholars Foundation where we just launched a program called Emerge, which helps to place students of color, first gen students, low income students, into companies across this city, to expose them to financial markets and other companies like Loop Capital.</p>
<p>I am sitting here as living proof of an internship program. I think back to when I started interning – the CEO paid me out of his pocket.  And John Rogers and Melody Hobson over at Ariel Investments have started a school. So when you think about the commitment here, the desire for minority students in particular to have exposure to this business, we are following suit via not only our wallets, but also our time, effort and energy, to make sure that we’re not the last faces of color you see in these seats – and that we continue to grow and foster students across this city.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>Are there some of those internships here at Loop Capital?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> Definitely. Right now, our internship program brings in either sophomores or juniors in college. We have a huge internship talent pool – over a thousand applicants this past year that wanted to work at Loop Capital. Unfortunately, we couldn&#8217;t take them all in, but we do usually have between 20 and 30 students every single summer that we bring in to expose to investment banking.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong> <strong>What are some of the things that they do within the internship?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> It varies – whatever we need. Candidly, if I needed to go do something that isn&#8217;t normally what you would see a president do – say we have a pitch and everyone else is working on something – I&#8217;ll go in the back and put the books together.</p>
<p>It really is a roll-up-your-sleeves kind of business, and at the end of the day the ultimate objective is to add value to your clients, which ultimately adds value to the firm…which ultimately makes sure that we can offer jobs and internships to folks such as yourself in the future.</p>
<p>There are a myriad of things that interns here get exposure to, from putting together those pitch books to burning the midnight oil running models and working in Excel and PowerPoint. And we bring our interns to meetings – whether it&#8217;s with a CEO or the mayor of the city, we&#8217;ll bring our interns to expose them to what actually happens at the other end. So, you’re working all night running models and doing pitch books – well, how does that come to life in a meeting? We really try to expose our students to the full gamut of what it is to work at an investment bank.</p>
<h2><strong>YA:</strong>  <strong>I&#8217;m a junior in high school and I have to deal with a lot of things, such as school and taking the SAT, but also, I want to enhance my understanding of the financial industry. Is there any advice you have for me that I can be able to manage both my school and learning about the financial industry?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> Prioritize.</p>
<p>Like I said – and I don&#8217;t care if it&#8217;s Loop Capital, if it&#8217;s Morgan Stanley, if it&#8217;s Citadel, if it&#8217;s Ariel – when you first come through that door you have to be on par and as good, if not better, than the folks who are already in that job. The first thing people are going to say is “OK, what’s is your GPA? What were your test scores? And maybe you didn&#8217;t go to Harvard or Yale, and that&#8217;s OK – but you went to school and you worked incredibly hard, you got great grades ,you were active and involved. You were involved in your community, and you showed an interest early on in this business.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s how you shape that total package that then comes in the door says, &#8220;Hey. I&#8217;m the person you want to hire.&#8221; You want to make sure you’re doing those things that give you a leg up in this world. So, if you want to be a fund manager and run your own portfolio, look at what the background is of those fund managers you aspire to be like. Then say, <br />“How can I put my career path on par with theirs? What did they do to get to where they are, and how can I put myself in a position to do similar things?</p>
<p><strong>YA:</strong> Thank you very much Ms. Gibson – thank you for being here today and allowing us to interview you.</p>
<p><strong>KG:</strong> Thank you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 7</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>150 Years Later&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 16:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6412</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Things that turn 150 years old in 2019: The Periodic Table Professional baseball UCAN! We happen to think UCAN is as innovative and original as our 150 year-old compatriots. But how does one innovatively celebrate such a milestone? We kicked off our celebrations exactly 150 days prior to our birthday with the launch of a...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/" title="Read 150 Years Later&#8230;">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/">150 Years Later&#8230;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Things that turn 150 years old in 2019:</p>
<ul>
<li style="list-style-type: none;">
<ul>
<li>The Periodic Table</li>
<li>Professional baseball</li>
<li>UCAN!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>We happen to think UCAN is as innovative and original as our 150 year-old compatriots. But how does one innovatively celebrate such a milestone?</p>
<p>We kicked off our celebrations exactly 150 days prior to our birthday with the launch of a <a href="http://150anniversary.ucanchicago.org/">microsite solely dedicated to our extensive history</a>. In 1869 we were called the &#8220;Uhlich Evangelical Orphan Asylum&#8221; but as the years passed, we thought UCAN had a better ring to it. Along with the microsite, we rolled out  &#8220;UCAN&#8217;s 150 Facts&#8221; campaign where we posted a fact about UCAN&#8217;s history on social media every day until our birthday on March 29. You can check out a collection of them <a href="https://www.pinterest.com/ucanchicagoland/150-facts-about-ucan/">here</a>. </p>
<img class="alignright wp-image-6416 " src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-768x665.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="312" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-768x665.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-268x232.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-320x277.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-966x836.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-720x623.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-290x251.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0900-e1556640962988-369x319.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 360px) 100vw, 360px" />
<p>As fun as it is to highlight UCAN&#8217;s rich history, we also wanted to honor the dedicated employees who continually help move UCAN into the future. Each month, our President/CEO Zack Schrantz presents a select, small group of employees with the 150th Anniversary President&#8217;s Coin to recognize the recipient&#8217;s spirit, service and teamwork they demonstrate to support UCAN’s pursuit of our vision and mission. </p>
<p>We also unveiled our new UCAN 150th anniversary logo along with lamp post banners lining the street outside of our North Lawndale campus and our office on Western Avenue. Coincidentally (or not), the North Lawndale community is also celebrating its 150<sup>th</sup> anniversary this year.</p>
<p>March was a particularly busy month. Our staff members showed their silly side by dressing up for a different theme like Superhero day and Hippie day. The week culminated with our annual Employee Banquet (this year we celebrated in Roaring ‘20s style!). </p>
<img class=" wp-image-6420 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2.png" alt="" width="289" height="231" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2.png 945w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-268x214.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-768x614.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-320x256.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-720x576.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-290x232.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/UCAN-SPIRIT-WEEK-DAY-2-369x295.png 369w" sizes="(max-width: 289px) 100vw, 289px" />
<p>For our 150th birthday on March 29, we started the day with a party featuring delicious cupcakes, games, music, and perhaps most importantly, celebrating one another and the work we collectively carry out to support the youth, families and communities we serve. </p>
<p>The celebrations did not stop there for later that night, we reached the crescendo of months of work and preparation: the 150th Anniversary Celebration held at the Chicago History Museum. We brought old photos and items, like our accounts ledger from 1890, for guests to peak through, along with a historical yearbook for guests to sign. Everyone was treated to drinks, food and even a performance by the founders of UCAN Voices: Fred Long, Jason Daniels, and Vic Spencer. While the  evening centered on the history of UCAN, our guests understood that we were also celebrating the future.</p>
<img class="wp-image-6423 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717.jpg" alt="" width="469" height="312" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717.jpg 2500w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/IMG_1717-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 469px) 100vw, 469px" />
<p>And we have more to come!</p>
<p>We are looking forward to the expansion of our Healing Garden, Petria&#8217;s Place, located on our Drost Harding Campus in North Lawndale near our youth home. We are installing a brick path that you can also support! To purchase a brick or for more information, <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/150th-anniversary-brick-collection/">click here</a>.</p>
<p>We are looking forward to an event-filled six months and hope you will join us at our 20th annual <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/yla/">Youth Leadership Awards on June 6</a>, help us celebrate the opening of Petria’s Place, contribute to a symposium focused on women’s influence in UCAN’s history, and kick back with us at our youth-centric Peace Fest on June 26.</p>
<p><em>By Carly Hanson</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/">150 Years Later&#8230;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/05/150-years-later/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 19:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6280</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>A doctor. An actor. A businessman. A reporter. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/">Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A doctor. An actor. A businessman. A reporter. </p>
<p>Four unique aspirations of four unique youth.</p>
<p>UCAN supporter and marketing consultant, Chuck Kent, had an idea to help make those dreams a reality: give youth the opportunity to have a discussion with a professional who works in the field the youth aspires to develop a career. The idea grew into a series of videos in which UCAN youth interview notable Chicago professionals about their respective careers and industry.</p>
<p>These conversations not only explore how one gets into such work, but why and how that career is valuable to the city and its people. It’s all part of our conviction at UCAN that today’s youth, even when faced with trauma, can become tomorrow’s leaders.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more episodes!</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6033 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 1</a></h1>
<p><em>The interviewer for our inaugural episode is Ariyan Moore, currently a marketing student, who spoke with </em><em>John </em><em>Starkey</em><em>, Global Brand Leader for Dove and Galaxy chocolates at </em><em>Mars</em><em>. </em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6123 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 2</a></h1>
<p><em>In our second episode, Briana Owens, an aspiring broadcaster and currently a student at Ithaca College interviews Brandis Griffith-Friedman, a correspondent and segment host for Chicago Tonight on WTTW, Chicago’s public television station.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/">here</a>. </p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6118 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 3</a></h1>
<p><em>In the third episode, Ebonie Henderson, an aspiring actress, visits the Goodman Theater to interview Henry Godinez, Resident Artistic Associate and a professor at Northwestern University.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/">here</a>. </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-6189 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-268x144.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="144" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-268x144.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-768x412.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-320x172.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-966x518.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-720x386.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-290x156.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-369x198.jpg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></a><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">Watch Episode 4</a></h1>
<p><em>In the fourth episode, Maya Hunter, a UCAN participant who aspires to be a physician, interviews Dr. Perpetua Goodall, an Associate Professor of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology at the University of Chicago.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/">Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6279</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>"Today we are celebrating Dr. King while also coming out to support our community,” said Nadine Toussaint, a student at UIC. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/">Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the growing Civil Rights Movement incited detractors in 1959, many faith leaders in Chicago feared backlash and refused to allow Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. to preach to their congregations. Reverend James Marcellus Stone, then pastor of Stone Temple Baptist Church, welcomed Dr. King to preach, knowing that a message of justice and love should be welcomed in his church.</p>
<p>On January 26 of 1966, one year after declaring Chicago the epicenter of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference&#8217;s civil rights efforts in the north, Dr. King and his wife Coretta moved to a quaint apartment on the West Side of the city in North Lawndale, across the street from the Stone Temple Baptist Church. Stone Temple would go on to become Dr. King’s &#8220;action center&#8221; for the Civil Rights Movement. Though Dr. King&#8217;s apartment is gone, Stone Temple continues to be a pillar in North Lawndale, the home of UCAN’s headquarters.</p>
<img class="alignright wp-image-6284 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-268x357.jpeg" alt="" width="268" height="357" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-268x357.jpeg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-768x1024.jpeg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-320x427.jpeg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-966x1288.jpeg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-720x960.jpeg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-290x387.jpeg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-369x492.jpeg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180.jpeg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
<p>For the annual ‘MLK Day of Service,’ observed on Dr. King’s  birthday, the University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC) Student Leadership and Civic Engagement&#8217;s office reached out to UCAN ready to give back to their community. </p>
<p>&#8220;We had the opportunity to engage UIC students in North Lawndale and felt that our community needed the support more than us,We build up and support youth who’ve suffered trauma,&#8221; says Andrea Lee, Manager of External Affairs Manager at UCAN. &#8220;We work with youth themselves, their families, and their community – like with this project. We had the chance to lead this service project to support pillar in our community of North Lawndale that continues to be an ‘action center’ – of spirituality and community connectedness. In addition to supporting the youth through our programs, we recognize that supporting other community institutions is another critical way to build strong youth and families.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fifty students from UIC arrived at Stone Temple Baptist Church on January 21<sup>st</sup> ready to paint, organize, deep clean, and repair floors.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today we are celebrating Dr. King while also coming out to support our community,” said Nadine Toussaint, a student at UIC. </p>
<p>Though many people across the country participate in the MLK Day of Service, the UIC students’ day of service was unique in that they gave back to the same community that Dr. King embraced as his own decades before.</p>
<p>“It was really great because some of the community members of the church were hanging out to see what we were doing and encouraging us and thanking us for being there,&#8221; says Samantha Lagestee, another UIC student.</p>
<p>By the end of the day, the volunteers had painted two large conference rooms, washed walls in high-traffic hallways, organized the storage room and deep-cleaned the storage area.</p>
<p>“I am grateful for UCAN. I am grateful for the students that came from UIC,&#8221; says Pastor Reshorna Fitzpatrick of Stone Temple. &#8220;I’m just excited today, it’s just a beautiful project taking place. I’m sure if Dr. King was alive he’d be happy to see all of us coming together in one place having a united front.”</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=369657973867386">Check out UIC&#8217;s video recapping their Day of Service!</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/">Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mentees to Mentors</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 15:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Employees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6181</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>At the very core of UCAN is youth development. It’s the underlying constant within each program, and of the tools used to support their development, mentoring remains one of the strongest and most effective. “Mentor” can mean someone who you look up to or someone you aspire to be. It can be someone who pushes...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/" title="Read Mentees to Mentors">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/">Mentees to Mentors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the very core of UCAN is youth development. It’s the underlying constant within each program, and of the tools used to support their development, mentoring remains one of the strongest and most effective.</p>
<p>“Mentor” can mean someone who you look up to or someone you aspire to be. It can be someone who pushes you or someone who supports you whether a family member or a colleague. </p>
<p>But for two youth at UCAN, mentor means someone who has changed their lives.</p>
<p>Seantayvia Byrd came to UCAN two years ago through the Violence Intervention and Prevention Services program. Now she is a senior in high school and looking forward to her future with the support of her Youth Development Coach Nadia Hill. </p>
<p>“I know that she cares &#8211; for real,” says Seantayvia of Nadia.</p>
<p>As Seantayvia navigates her last year of school, she’s looked to Nadia for help in making decisions about her future. Though she hasn’t applied to college yet, she plans to attend, and when the time comes, Nadia will be there to assist her in the application process and beyond. Her goal: become a psychologist.</p>
<p>Yasmine Kirkwood, another UCAN youth, shares Seantayvia’s enthusiasm for psychology.  She cites her therapist as her mentor.</p>
<p>“I just love her,” Yasmine says. “She gave me more confidence; she helped me come out of my shell. She’s my inspiration. I don’t know what I’d do without her.”</p>
<p>Because of the support and guidance Yasmine received from her therapist after her father died, she knew this is what she&#8217;s meant to do: help people like her. &#8220;Making other people feel good, it helps me.&#8221;</p>
<p>“It’s good to have a person like that outside of your family,” Seantayvia adds.</p>
<p>Nadia Hill is herself a mentee having spent most of her life in North Lawndale. From a young age, she was active in after school programs such as the Boys and Girls Club. </p>
<p>&#8220;[My mother] was very intentional,” she says, “to make sure I was very involved with community,&#8221; and that connection is a reason she became a youth development coach.</p>
<p>&#8220;It doesn&#8217;t matter who I work with,&#8221; says Nadia. &#8220;I want them to see that they can be self-sufficient.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/">Mentees to Mentors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Can Survive</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 22:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6208</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>UCAN offers services that focus on mental health, from traditional therapy to expressive acting and art programs, but healing is at common theme in our programming.  UCAN Survive is a new program funded via a ICJIA (Illinois Criminal Justice Information Authority)/VOCA (Victims of Crime Act) grant that is dedicated to healing and supporting victims or...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/" title="Read You Can Survive">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/">You Can Survive</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UCAN offers services that focus on mental health, from traditional therapy to expressive acting and art programs, but healing is at common theme in our programming. </p>
<p>UCAN Survive is a new program funded via a ICJIA (Illinois Criminal Justice Information Authority)/VOCA (Victims of Crime Act) grant that is dedicated to healing and supporting victims or witnesses of crime.</p>
<p>&#8220;We keep the same foundation of UCAN,&#8221; says Janay Brinkley, a UCAN youth development coach. &#8220;We believe traumatized youth and families can become leaders as well, but combine that with ICIJA/VOCA (and) we serve victims of crime. That ranges anywhere from burglary, arson, domestic abuse, sexual abuse, harassment; even if you witnessed a crime or experienced a homicide, you’d fall under this service. We deal with clients 13 and up.&#8221;</p>
<p>Janay moved to Chicago from Maryland in 2017. &#8220;I felt like I was being called to Chicago,&#8221; she says. Though she had not previously worked in a nonprofit, she joined the UCAN team in April 2018, specifically to be trained and work under the UCAN Survive program.</p>
<p>“What makes us different from other development coaches,&#8221; she explains, &#8220;is that we are like a hybrid that includes mentorship, case management and a form of counseling. We kind of do all three in one.”</p>
<p>The grant allows for 10 youth development coaches, five under Violence Intervention and Prevention Services and five under Counseling and Youth Development, the latter of which is where Janay works. </p>
<p>“We help them with goal setting, jobs, and educational advocacy. We have youth who need us to step in for parent counseling, or help with court, or help with restraining order paperwork. We are your coach, we are your mentor, we are your therapist, and we are your caseworker,” says Janay. &#8220;We want to work smarter not harder. UCAN has group programs like Phenomenal Woman and Project Visible Man. Let&#8217;s do that same group type setting with UCAN Survive.&#8221;</p>
<p>UCAN piloted a group UCAN Survive program in which individual clients come together monthly in a group setting to address and practice healthy self-coping skills, self-care, confidence, education on the criminal justice system, and encourage hope for the future.</p>
<p>“There have been a lot of success stories,” says Janay. &#8220;There was a client (and) she was a walk-in. She heard about the program and was assigned to my coworker, Ashley . The woman explained that she was walking around with three kids and a newborn baby, living in her car. That day, Ashley helped her get basic needs at the store, gave her the information she needed and helped her get into a shelter. I was in awe of that story. She was support, she was her case manager, she gave her shelter and she gave her tangible thing she needed, all within that day.&#8221;</p>
<p>The development coaches have since worked out a system in which one coach has a specified strength that helps determine which client is assigned to whom, whether helping with housing accommodations, employment or mentoring,. </p>
<p>But Janay noticed one unexpected pattern in her clients.</p>
<p>“Sometimes, what really means the most to the client &#8230; it&#8217;s just the time spent.&#8221;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/">You Can Survive</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 4</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6188</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest. In the fourth episode of our series, Maya Hunter, a UCAN participant who aspires to be a physician, interviews Dr. Perpetua Goodall, an Associate Professor of Obstetrics &#38; Gynecology at...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/" title="Read Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 4">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 4</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<div id="content" class="style-scope ytd-expander">
<div id="description" class="style-scope ytd-video-secondary-info-renderer">In the fourth episode of our series, Maya Hunter, a UCAN participant who aspires to be a physician, interviews Dr. Perpetua Goodall, an Associate Professor of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology at the University of Chicago. It’s a fascinating discussion – please watch the video and read the full interview in text.</div>
<div> </div>
<div class="style-scope ytd-video-secondary-info-renderer">Find other episodes <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cIx01_S_HOM" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2><strong>Maya Hunter:</strong> Thank you for being with us today, Dr. Goodall. Could you briefly introduce yourself and tell us what you do?</h2>
<p><strong>Perpetua Goodall, M.D.:</strong> Well, thank you Maya, for inviting me to talk with you. It&#8217;s my pleasure to get to know you and tell you about my work. I&#8217;m Dr. Perpetua Goodall, and I&#8217;m an obstetrician-gynecologist here at the University of Chicago. I&#8217;ve been in practice here for going on 18 years, and what I do is a combination of things. I do obstetric care, which is providing prenatal care to women as they go through their pregnancy. I provide care for them during their childbirth, and then afterwards. As a gynecologist, I focus on preventive health care for women, and I also take care of conditions that affect the reproductive system of women.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong> Why did you choose your specialty of medicine?</h2>
<p><strong>PG: </strong>I think that OB/GYN combines an opportunity to provide primary care for women, and it also gives you an opportunity to do procedures ( I really like working with my hands). So, I have a lot of variety in my day. I get to see women from adolescence through the menopause, and so might go into one room to see a teenager coming in to talk about contraception and walk into another room and talk to a 65-year-old who’s dealing with menopause. Or I&#8217;ll go meet with a 40-year-old dealing with conditions like abnormal bleeding or fibroid tumors.</p>
<p>I get to see a lot of different types of patients from different backgrounds, and so I think OB/GYN is a very special experience.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong> What do you like most about your medical practice?</h2>
<p><strong>PG:</strong> I really enjoy the patients – talking to them, getting to connect with them on a personal level. Patients are sharing some of the most intimate details of their lives with you, so it really gives you an opportunity to develop meaningful relationships over time. And I take pleasure in getting to know families, taking care of moms, daughters, sisters, aunts…taking care of their families and their communities.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong> Besides seeing patients, you are also a professor – so what do you like about teaching?</h2>
<p><strong>PG:</strong>  Teaching is rewarding on a number of fronts.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s nice to see students grow over time, to have an influence on a future generation of healthcare providers and doctors, and to share the knowledge that I&#8217;ve developed over time. I also like being able to continue to develop my own knowledge and improve and grow. So, it’s rewarding both as a student and as a teacher.</p>
<p>It also gives you an opportunity to give back or contribute to the system that helped you get to where you are.</p>
<p>The other thing I like is that it keeps you on your toes. Being a teacher, you have to keep up with research and up-to-date practice, and so I think it really makes me a better clinician in that, if I&#8217;m able to explain a complex topic to a medical student, it makes it easier for me to explain that information to my patients.</p>
<p>It’s also nice to have students come along with me when I&#8217;m seeing patient, to learn from me at the bedside. It&#8217;s a special experience to be able to share my knowledge with others and help the growth and development of young learners.</p>
<h2><strong>MH</strong>: I want to become an OB/GYN. What steps do I need to take to see if I&#8217;m really passionate about becoming a doctor?</h2>
<p><strong>PG:</strong> For starters, take advantage of opportunities like this, to talk to doctors in different specialties. You may find that OB/GYN is not what you have a passion for. You could shadow an internal medicine doctor, a pediatrician, a surgeon. Take every opportunity possible to talk to different doctors in different specialties and types of practices. There&#8217;s academic medicine, which is what I practice, and then there&#8217;s private practice, where people practice out in the community, and have a little more autonomy and control.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong>  What do you think are some qualities of being a good physician?</h2>
<p><strong>PG:</strong> Number one is being a caring and compassionate person. You have to empathize and connect with people and put yourself in their position. Try to understand their situations, their communities, and be able to connect with them on a personal level. It’s relatively easy to learn technical, objective information or scientific information – but the doctor-patient relationship is founded on that personal connection</p>
<p>So, the qualities that I would most expect to find in a good physician would be caring, compassionate, empathetic, and then knowledgeable, competent and confident – but not arrogant. Someone that you can relate to and have confidence in but not feel that they&#8217;re not approachable.</p>
<h2><strong>MH</strong>: Finally, why do you think that the careers in medicine are important to the future of Chicago?</h2>
<p><strong>PG</strong>: Wow. You can look at this as not just limited to Chicago. The health of society has so many effects on other aspects of a community, like productivity, economic development, and education. If you&#8217;re not healthy, you&#8217;re not able to contribute to your community or to your society.</p>
<p>Doctors play an extremely important role in maintaining and establishing healthy communities. They provide education about preventative healthcare strategies and maintaining your health. And it’s also about treating health conditions and providing access to quality providers who care about their community.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s extremely important that people like you want to go into the field. You know, looking at the number of minority physicians, well, it’s still an area where work needs to be done. Studies have actually shown that minority patients may do better when they have a provider that looks like them. So, it&#8217;s important to have, or to recruit, people like you who want to give back to their communities, who want to practice in their communities.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong> Well thank you Dr. Goodall for being here and taking time out of your day.</h2>
<p><strong>Catch up on previous episodes of “Chicago’s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today,” and watch UCAN youth interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>:</strong></p>
<p>John Starkey, Global Brand Lead for Dove Chocolates at Mars<br />Brandis Friedman, Segment Host at WTTW, Channel 11<br />Henry Godinez, Resident Artistic Associate at The Goodman Theatre</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 4</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voices Raised Stronger, Last Longer</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 17:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6129</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2002, lightning struck within the halls of UCAN. Three young men took their friendship and talent to new heights by founding the Uhlich Voices program.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/">Voices Raised Stronger, Last Longer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2002, lightning struck within the halls of UCAN. Three young men took their friendship and talent to new heights by founding the Uhlich Voices program, which is in resurgence and rebranded today as UCAN Voices.</p>
<p>In its infancy, Voices was simply a way for three young men from Chicago’s South Side – Fred Long, Jason Daniels and Victor Spencer – to bond through their passion for song writing, freestyle rap and musical expression.  </p>
<p>Jason started his musical journey near the Rainbow Beach neighborhood in Chicago, playing the violin in the second grade. At the time he was pushed into it by his grandmother, but grew to look forward to the lessons. Facing the turmoil of having two brothers incarcerated, gang fights and gun violence in the streets, Jason spent most of his time in his room practicing violin and writing song lyrics.  Soon he built up the confidence to perform in talent shows at school and found himself surrounded by crowds of his peers as he practiced free style rapping in the lunch room. <img class="size-full wp-image-6132 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4980_93000759305_5482977_n.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4980_93000759305_5482977_n.jpg 300w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4980_93000759305_5482977_n-268x201.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4980_93000759305_5482977_n-290x218.jpg 290w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>This love of music was what soon connected Jason to Fred. Although they went to high school together, both were so focused on keeping their heads down and away from trouble on the streets that they didn’t discover their kinship until playing as teammates on East West College’s basketball team. That’s when Fred introduced Jason to his longtime friend Vic and the three became inseparable, recording dozens of mix tapes in Victor’s apartment that was then part of UCAN’s Transitional Living Program.</p>
<p>“I was a natural show-off,” Jason says.  “But Fred would not rap outside of his laundry room, Vic’s house or on the bus. You could tell he wanted to get into the rap battles I was getting into but he would never do it. So Uhlich Voices was kind of like his coming out party.”</p>
<p>For 6-8 months, the young men cataloged the best songs from their repertoire that could be perfected and combined into a published album. With the help of UCAN’s Executive Vice President Claude Robinson, they learned how to find and network with music industry representatives and secured grant funding from Amistad Foundation to start the recording process in 2004. Once their album was released, the group toured coast to coast for almost three years, performing for crowds of thousands.</p>
<p>Flash forward to 2018: Vic Spencer’s musical career is still on the rise. His album is listed on the top 40 independent charts and he has worked with some of the most lauded artists in the rap music industry, including Chance the Rapper, Mick Jenkins, Vic Mensa and Red Man. His most recent release is a feature on Ghostface Killah’s new album.</p>
<p>Fred Long has also become an example of how UCAN builds future leaders. UCAN offered him an internship after his time in care, and he worked his way through the ranks to become vice president of Development, managing a team of seven to secure resources to contribute to UCAN’s budget of over $40 million to support youth and families in need.  </p>
<p><img class="alignleft wp-image-6137 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-268x268.png" alt="" width="268" height="268" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-268x268.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-150x150.png 150w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-768x768.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-320x320.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-720x720.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-290x290.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-369x369.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-125x125.png 125w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />During the height of their recording efforts, Jason moved to New York City to make a name for himself as a songwriter.  Unfortunately, he found out quickly that without extensive knowledge of the music industry, you can be taken advantage of and left with little means for survival. It was his experiences in New York that brought him back to UCAN with a deeper and more passionate interest in protecting and educating the youth we serve. Jason is currently a youth development coach at UCAN and one of the main parties responsible for bringing the Voices program back into prominence.</p>
<p>Under Jason’s guidance, Voices’ meetings allow for a fun and free-spirited atmosphere without losing any structure or momentum in its therapeutic objectives. Youth rotate every other week between learning the ins and outs of the music business and the tools for engineering, beat making and expressive writing. The other weeks are devoted to recording and allowing each young person to share their story.</p>
<p>Jason says he’s been amazed week to week at the progress our young people make. One youth, James, recently needed a push to realize his potential.  “Before we started Voices I was working with James as a mentor. He had a severe speech impediment. He was very withdrawn and couldn’t make eye contact. One way that I would try to connect with him when I would pick him up from school was playing him songs. He liked blues and some other stuff like that. I thought … let me try something with him. So I started freestylin’ over some instrumentals. It became a thing with us and every time I would pick him up he was looking ready with a new beat to try writing lyrics for.”</p>
<p>The next step was to get James to understand how to work through some his unanswered questions in his life, like his relationship with his father that had put a strain on his development throughout his adolescence.  “A lot of things that have happened to James, he is still searching for answers to. Unfortunately he might not ever get those answers. But music has helped him tremendously with his speech. Within a year you can hardly tell he ever had a stutter or difficulty communicating,” adds Jason.</p>
<p>Jason explains that the Voices program’s goals and expectations have shifted slightly since his time as a member. He plans to host performances and find ways for youth to boost their confidence through recording. But the bulk of the program focuses on therapeutically learning about life through the ins and outs of the music business, and driving home the value of being able to tell your story in a way that other people cannot.</p>
<p>“It is how I got through my hard times when my father was on drugs and I was having a lot of resentment towards him. I had so much anger towards him that I couldn’t bring myself to just sit down and talk with him,” Jason recalls. “I remember writing the song ‘Fathers’ Day’ and just crying. It wasn’t even sadness; it was a release and a weight off of me to express those feelings.”</p>
<p>Jason wants the future of UCAN Voices to provide a similar release for many more youth looking for answers to difficult questions in their lives. “The thing about music is it is a universal language. It takes the power away from those who have hurt you,” Jason says.  “And these youth are learning SO much that they don’t realize will be valuable for their life down the road.”</p>
<p>Thanks to new funding from the Chicago Chapter of The Links Inc., and a blended partnership with UCAN’s Express Therapy program, UCAN Voices is seeing growth in membership and success. If you have an interest in music, spoken word or the performing arts, we welcome guest speakers, volunteers and recommendations for additional funding sources to keep this special resource available to the youth and families we serve.</p>
<p><em>By Ann Kniola</em></p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hhhQ9u0Jpl0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/">Voices Raised Stronger, Last Longer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mini Grants, Max Impact</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 18:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6071</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Summer means sun, fun and no school. But unfortunately, summer in Chicago also has come to mean a spike in gun violence in too many neighborhoods. In response, to provide youth with engaging activities in safe spaces that raise awareness of the risks and positively support youth, the MacArthur Foundation awarded UCAN 12 mini grants...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/" title="Read Mini Grants, Max Impact">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/">Mini Grants, Max Impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Summer means sun, fun and no school. But unfortunately, summer in Chicago also has come to mean a spike in gun violence in too many neighborhoods. In response, to provide youth with engaging activities in safe spaces that raise awareness of the risks and positively support youth, the MacArthur Foundation awarded UCAN 12 mini grants to fund youth-led projects in North Lawndale during summer 2018. </p>
<p>Check out what each youth group did with their grant:</p>
<div style="width: 640px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-6071-1" width="640" height="427" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/90111-WLS-2018-10-28-0534-UCAN-00m36s-1.mp4?_=1" /><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/90111-WLS-2018-10-28-0534-UCAN-00m36s-1.mp4">http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/90111-WLS-2018-10-28-0534-UCAN-00m36s-1.mp4</a></video></div>
<ol>
<li><u>Kingdom Builder&#8217;s Christian Center</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Kingdom Builder’s Christian Center held a Gun Violence Awareness Rally on August 18 where the project’s youth leaders held a uniform and school supplies giveaway along with fun activities and food to promote unity in the community. The youth experienced the satisfaction of putting on a large event and made a difference in the community.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><u>Sankofa Safe Child Initiative</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Sankofa Safe Child Initiative held a “Girls Speak Out Task Force” forum on August 24. A group of young women watched the film “Hidden Figures” and held a discussion on the topic of self-love and self-esteem. The goals were to decrease violence through discussion, education, and participation. The youth who presented the forum were empowered and learned leadership and service skills, values and commitment.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><u>SAIC – The Art Institute at Homan Square </u></li>
</ol>
<p>The School of the Art Institute of Chicago (SAIC) partnered with the Drums, No Guns foundation to host three “Junkyard Jam” workshops on August 15, 17, and 18. The workshops focused on rhythm, music, and art to promote nonviolence and peace in the community. The youth helped to lead bucket drumming classes and mural painting to use music, art and dialogue to process the causes, symptoms and consequences of collective trauma as a result of violence.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><u>SAIC- The Art Institute at Homan Square </u></li>
</ol>
<p>The School of the Art Institute of Chicago (SAIC) partnered with the African Heritage Garden to host a non-violence community celebration and volunteer workday. The anti-violence community celebration’s objective was to engage local residents to raise public awareness of city-wide anti-violence initiatives, promotes reflection upon cultural heritage and ancestry, and encourage holistic well-being.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><u>Harmony Church</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Harmony Church held a “Peace Jam”, promoting peace and non-violence, on August 25. The youth conducted an anti-violence prayer session with the community and provided members of the North Lawndale community with school backpacks, food, music, and hosted outdoor activities. The goals? Help the youth leaders build on their leadership skills, allow residents to enjoy a safe space, and support the youth leaders in making informed decisions to prevent trauma and violence in their lives.</p>
<img class="size-medium wp-image-6100 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
<ol start="6">
<li><u>Strategic Human Services</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Strategic Human Services/NLCN held many “Dance for Peace” block club parties throughout North Lawndale featuring free entertainment and peace messages. The youth participated in something bigger than themselves, gained larger roles in the community and met new people.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="7">
<li><u>Boxing Out Negativity</u><img class="size-medium wp-image-6097 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></li>
</ol>
<p>Boxing Out Negativity held a “Gloves, Not Guns” and a “Bike Ride for Peace” on July 4 and August 11, respectively and educated youth on the topic of gun violence and promoted peace in North Lawndale. Youth built a sense of team, cultivated leadership skills, provided a platform for sharing community resources, and inspired positive action among youth through anti-violence dance.</p>
<ol start="8">
<li><u>Chicago Youth Centers (CYC)</u></li>
</ol>
<img class="size-medium wp-image-6098 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
<p>Chicago Youth Centers (CYC) held a Chicago Ideas Day anti-violence “Play Streets” event and youth leaders led an anti-violence march in North Lawndale in the summer. The youth worked together, marched without violence, built a sense of community, to demonstrate to the adults see why non-violence important.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="9">
<li><u>The Night Ministry (Phoenix Hall) and Loveren Collections</u></li>
</ol>
<p>The Night Ministry and Loveren Collections collaborated and held four workshops in August focusing on conversations in healing, violence, and self-love. The goals were to empower people by learning about their bodies, share skills, and heal from past trauma and low self-esteem as a result of violence. The youth were inspired to blossom into entrepreneurs in a space for creative growth and leadership.</p>
<ol start="10">
<li><u>Grace and Glory Tabernacle Church <img class="size-medium wp-image-6107 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></u></li>
</ol>
<p>Grace and Glory Church held a neighborhood cookout and hosted vacation Bible schools throughout the month of July to bring youth from from the streets to enjoy team-building exercises and skills, while improving their reading and communication skills.</p>
<ol start="11">
<li><u>Community Christian Academy (CCA)</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Community Christian Academy (CCA) held an Anti-violence Registration Fair on August 23 to encourage youth to enroll in and get motivated about school. Support from peers motivated the students and helped them see the importance of pursuing academic success. The youth acted as leaders and engaged their peers by refocusing their energy on positive and life-changing goals.</p>
<ol start="12">
<li><u>Forward Thinking Mentoring</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Forward Thinking held a festive block party in September to bring the North Lawndale community together in non-violent activities focused on unity.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/">Mini Grants, Max Impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
				<enclosure url="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/90111-WLS-2018-10-28-0534-UCAN-00m36s-1.mp4" length="21806233" type="video/mp4" />
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Year of the Volunteer</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 21:04:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6080</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>We all know time can pass by us in a blur. That is why we give special praise to those who slow down, take some time to reflect, and give a little bit of their most cherished resource… their time.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/">The Year of the Volunteer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all know time can pass by us in a blur. That is why we give special praise to those who slow down, take some time to reflect, and give a little bit of their most cherished resource… their time.</p>
<p>#TwitterForGood Day happens twice a year around the globe.  This year Twitter conducted over 76 service projects across 16 offices around the world. In Chicago a group of 20 “Tweeps” helped UCAN spruce up their conference rooms by painting Chicago neighborhood murals.</p>
<img class="wp-image-6079 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954.jpg" alt="" width="272" height="363" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954.jpg 2448w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-268x357.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-768x1024.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-320x427.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-966x1288.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-720x960.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-290x387.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/Painting-canvases-e1543610683954-369x492.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 272px) 100vw, 272px" />
<p>Twitter was built to foster communication on a global scale because they believe the open exchange of information can be a compelling force for good in the world.  The mission for corporate philanthropy at Twitter is to reflect and augment the positive power of their platform through civic engagement, employee volunteerism, charitable contributions, and in-kind donations.  In these ways, their company can foster greater understanding, equality and opportunities available in cities where they operate. </p>
<p>One of the volunteers from Twitter, Michelle Tomblin, reflected on her experience, “I personally loved getting a better feel for the great work that UCAN does for the Chicago community.  The staff at UCAN really made sure to educate Twitter Chicago on the many programs that UCAN offers including Project Visible Man, crisis prevention, therapy, etc.  I left there eager to find more opportunities where @TwitterChicago and UCAN can partner together in the near future in order to make an impact with the youth of Chicago!”</p>
<p>We’d like to give a virtual high five and pat on the back to our friends at Twitter as well as several other stellar groups of volunteers who went out of their way to give back where UCAN needed them most this year.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Allstate</strong> – As part of an annual conference, 25 senior leaders from Allstate, including UCAN Governing Board Member Mario Rizzo, painted the gym at UCAN Academy Grand, our therapeutic day school in Humboldt Park.
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-6077 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0503-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></li>
<li><strong>Aramark </strong>– In partnership with City Year, over 100 volunteers showed the value of a little elbow grease and beautified UCAN’s outdoor space with new benches, sports equipment and a mural during Aramark Building Community (ABC) Day. 
</li>
<li><strong>Kiser Group and Northern Trust</strong> – Donated treat bags and passed out candy to over 300 children trick or treating on Halloween in North Lawndale.
</li>
<li><strong>Delta Kappa Delta</strong> –The ladies of Delta Kappa Delta showed our staff their work is important by rejuvenating our Western Avenue office walls with fresh coats of paint.
</li>
<li><strong>US Bank – </strong>Four prominent leaders at US Bank took time to host a leadership conference for UCAN staff members.
</li>
<li><strong>4 Star Talent – </strong>Our new neighbors on the West Side collected over 300 gifts and toys to brighten the holidays for our youth and families this season. 
<img class="wp-image-6090 size-medium alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-320x214.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1-369x246.jpg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cinespace-1.jpg 640w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
</li>
<li><strong>Catherine Cook School</strong> – These thoughtful students proved knowledge is power by organizing a book drive spearheaded by UCAN Governing Board Vice Chairperson Susan McNally Wilde.</li>
<li><strong>Sigma Gamma Rho Sorority</strong> – Members of the Delta Sigma alumnae chapter collected over 300 pairs of new shoes for youth in UCAN&#8217;s Violence Intervention and Prevention Program.</li>
</ol>
<p>There is always more to do and we have the chance to make 2019’s volunteer initiatives bigger and more impactful! If your company, fraternity, social group or school wants to strengthen our Chicago community through volunteerism, please contact Andrea Lee at <a href="mailto:andrea.lee@ucanchicago.org">Andrea.Lee@UCANChicago.org</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/">The Year of the Volunteer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/the-year-of-the-volunteer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
