<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today &#8211; UCAN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/category/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org</link>
	<description>Youth who have suffered trauma can become our future leaders</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 18:50:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 18:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6380</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode a budding activist in the fight against food insecurity, interviews the Vice President of Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4o1OkmaWSXg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p><strong>How to fight hunger in Chicago and around the world</strong>. In this episode, Jade Wilkins, a budding activist in the fight against food insecurity (and a UCAN participant), interviews Nicole Robinson, Vice President of Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository. They discuss food insecurity, waste, hunger as a product of poverty and inequality, and hope ­– hope arising from a commitment to community.</p>
<p>Other Episodes can be found <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Jade Wilkins: Can you tell me a little bit about your role in the Chicago Food Depository and what you do here?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Nicole Robinson: </strong>I am the Vice President of what we call Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository, and I lead all of our programs, workforce development, and public policy programs. At the food depository, we are committed to ending hunger. We are one of 200 food banks across the country who do this work and we service the greater Chicagoland area within Cook County.</p>
<p>There are about 800,000 people who show up at food pantries, soup kitchens, and shelters across our service area and we help connect them to food, to work. And we help mobilize the public and raise awareness so that we can do something about ending hunger. It&#8217;s all about connecting people to the resources that they need.</p>
<p><strong>JW: That&#8217;s amazing. When I was here volunteering last year, I never would&#8217;ve noticed or imagined that the Greater Chicago Food Depository connects people to these different resources that allow them to get jobs as well as food. </strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you so much for volunteering at the food depository.</p>
<p><strong>JW: Of course.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you for that observation about that work, but Jade, when you think about it, hunger is a symptom of poverty. And when you think about a place like Chicago, some of the key issues we deal with in Chicago are poverty, racial inequity, and violence in our city – and hunger intersects with all of those things. In our work, we take all of that into consideration. If we&#8217;re going to end hunger, it&#8217;s really important for us to think about the economic impact and how we connect people to employment.</p>
<p>One of the programs we have that does that is a culinary training program called Chicago&#8217;s Community Kitchens. It&#8217;s 14 weeks long, and people learn here in our kitchen and in our classroom about the technical skills you need to work in the food industry. Then they get placed in a permanent job. We&#8217;re really proud of that work.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Wow. Why did you to join a nonprofit organization – specifically, the Greater Chicago Food Depository, working on humanitarian issues?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I&#8217;d say two things. One, I&#8217;ve been here about three years and, prior to that, I worked in the food industry. But I’m also a kid of Chicago Southside. I love Chicago, and I&#8217;ve been to other places in the world that deal with food insecurity and malnutrition. Although it has been striking, there are neighborhoods right in my backyard where young people, families, older adults all struggle with getting connected to food.</p>
<p>When I was a kid, I received something called SNAP. It used to be called food stamps and it’s a federal nutrition program where families can go into the grocery store and get the food that they need when they don&#8217;t have enough. So I am very personally aware of what that need is and how important it is to do something about it.</p>
<p>I want things to get better, I want families and individuals, young people to reach their full potential – and good nutrition, healthy food, is a big part of that.</p>
<p><strong>JW: I agree. My family was actually a part of that program at some time. We decided that we wanted to be more independent and not rely on government help by using SNAP or food stamps. That transition did make the situation a little bit worse for a short time. We&#8217;re still struggling, but it&#8217;s really good to make that transition and start developing that individuality. I really do understand that  – and that&#8217;s where my passion for food waste and this issue stems</strong> <strong>from.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I think your passion comes through on this issue for sure.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: </strong><strong>Thank you. Can for-profit organizations be as helpful as nonprofit organizations? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I think that, absolutely, corporations can be helpful in this effort, and we sometimes refer to them as public private partnerships, because nonprofits can&#8217;t do it alone. As an organization, we were actually designed to be an emergency resource for families, not their only source of food.Unfortunately, we&#8217;re  in a state where people come to us more than we actually think they need to, and we would like to make sure they&#8217;re connected to programs like SNAP that can get them the resources that they need.</p>
<p>But corporations are some of our number one partners, because 30 to 40 percent of the food we receive is donated to the food depository. We receive it from grocery stores like Jewel, Osco, Mariano&#8217;s, Aldi.</p>
<p>Starbucks is one of our biggest partners, and they have something called Food Share. They sell food in their stores – salads, sandwiches, fruit, pastries, all sorts of things – and every single day, we have a team of drivers who go to Starbucks stores overnight and they pick up all the food that&#8217;s left over from the previous day. That food goes directly to shelters in the Chicagoland area that are serving people impacted by homelessness.</p>
<p>None of that food goes to waste – and it was their idea to create that program. Starbucks approached us about this partnership.</p>
<p><strong>JW: That is incredible. I would&#8217;ve never imagined.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Most people don&#8217;t know that. Starbucks knew that they were going to sell food in their stores, but what they didn&#8217;t want to see was their unsold food going to waste.</p>
<h2><strong>JW:</strong> <strong>I am curious about one thing. You mentioned that there are grocers that donate food to the Greater Chicago Food Depository. I was wondering, what percentage of that food that would otherwise be wasted in those grocery stores gets donated?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> I don&#8217;t have the exact percentage, Jade, but I&#8217;d say that a good chunk of it is not wasted. Similar to the Starbucks program, what happens is the store managers in those Jewel, Osco, or Mariano&#8217;s stores, at the end of each week, collect the food that&#8217;s not saleable but still good and they save it for us. Then, we have drivers who go to the different stores across the Cook County area and pick up that food. The intent is to get as much as possible.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Right, what do you think happens to the remainder of that food if it is wasted – and why is it wasted?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> We try to get most of it, but what we also need to balance in the equation is that we&#8217;re putting trucks on the road to go get the food. So, for example, if there are only three sandwiches and you send a truck to get them…the cost-benefit analysis doesn’t really work.</p>
<p>But most times, we do get the food. And if we have partners with smaller quantities, those might go to pantry in their neighborhood. The pantry will partner with us and they will actually do the pickup of the food. I think we do our best to reduce the waste as much as possible – but it is about connecting families to the food, right?</p>
<p><strong>JW:  I recall there being an act that allows restaurants, grocers I believe, to be able to donate food.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> The Good Samaritan Act.</p>
<p><strong>JR: Yes!</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> You have done your research, Jade.</p>
<p><strong>JW:</strong><strong> I’ve delved really deep, I’m very passionate about this. I want to find a way to alter the policies that are causing all of this food waste. At my school, students have to pick up a certain amount of fruit or vegetables, and a lot of those students don&#8217;t eat that, so they end up throwing it away. I wanted to find a way other than going to collect it every day, something that&#8217;s more sustainable, something that can be carried on even after I leave Lane Tech.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong>  Did you mobilize students to collect the food that was going to waste?</p>
<p><strong>JW:  I did have a few people who were really interested in that. One student in particular saw me collecting food and they were inspired to do it as well. I&#8217;m unable to collect food during lunch because I have academic obligations. But, this one student goes around and collects the food in my absence, and he does it religiously. It&#8217;s amazing to see that. Honestly, when I saw that for the first time, I was almost moved to tears. Seeing someone else inspired by me inspired me some more.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Right, that&#8217;s what mobilizing the public around an issue is – and you sound like a food justice champion. We need more people like you to do this work. Yes, we&#8217;re partnering with corporations and government, but we still need so many individual people to be involved in this issue.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: One of my main goals in life is to establish my own nonprofit organization, kind of like what we have here at the Greater Chicago Food Depository, and I was wondering, what are the qualifications that you would need, or the qualities that make a successful nonprofit like this? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> There are two pieces to it. Part of it is that hunger has been around for a long time, and the food depository has been around for 40 years. We&#8217;ve been doing good work, but we know that there&#8217;s more to do — and we need to get at the root cause of some of these problems.</p>
<p>I think for someone like you who wants to start a nonprofit, you need to ask yourself, &#8220;What can I do differently?&#8221; And &#8220;What&#8217;s my niche?&#8221; What is the food depository missing, that&#8217;s not being done to serve the community? I think that&#8217;s a big opportunity for you. And part of it is just being curious, curious and listening to people in the community so you get a sense of what they really need so that you&#8217;re giving them the right solutions.</p>
<p><strong>JW: Definitely. I really want to be more involved in the community and I see the community as a family –  but it&#8217;s more like a divided family.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> That is part of the opportunity. How do we bring people together? A lot of times we talk at the food depository about going from transactional relationships to transformational. If we could just make our relationships at home, in the community, and at work transformational, we’d solve all the world&#8217;s problems.</p>
<p>In a world and in a city like Chicago, where there&#8217;s so much wealth, so much opportunity, I want to make sure that the opportunity is spread out, for everybody to reach their full potential, especially in the neighborhoods that today have the least.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: As we draw our interview to a close, I would really like to know, are there any role models in your life that have led you to become the person that you are today, involved in nonprofits such as the Greater Chicago Food Depository that work on issues like food insecurity and food waste?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Sure. Actually, some non-famous people, like teachers in elementary school. Mr. Boyd. And teachers in high school, Carol Gehring.</p>
<p>I had everyday role models. My mom&#8217;s a role model for me. She was a single mom. My grandmother is a role model as well for me because she worked really hard. She was part of something called The Great Migration, and she came from Arkansas for a better life for her and her children.</p>
<p>All of those women inspire me in my life. But then there are so many great women leaders in the city of Chicago. One I think you might be interested in became the head of the World Food Program. She was the first African American woman to lead the World Food Program which works in over 75 countries around the world. She lives right here in Chicago. That’s definitely someone I look up to when I think about this world of anti-hunger work.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Thank you so much for being with us today. It was really wonderful talking to you and learning more about the Greater Chicago Food Depository. </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> It was my pleasure to meet you, Jade. You are phenomenal at what you do, and you&#8217;re smart. Mind if I get a hug?</p>
<p><strong>JW: </strong><strong>Of course!</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you. Thank you for coming to the food depository to do this interview.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 5</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 20:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6309</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest. For our fifth interview, Caleb Hunter, a former UCAN participant and now a college sophomore studying Cybersecurity, met with Robert Matles, a technologist and Managing Director for J.P. Morgan Chase,...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/" title="Read Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 5">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 5</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p>For our fifth interview, Caleb Hunter, a former UCAN participant and now a college sophomore studying Cybersecurity, met with Robert Matles, a technologist and Managing Director for J.P. Morgan Chase, the global financial firm, who helps lead over 1800 technology professionals housed in seven very un-bank-like floors of the firm’s downtown Chicago office. They discussed what it takes to get into technology, what firms are looking for in new hires, and even whether or not Chicago will be the next Silicon Valley.</p>
<p>Find other episodes <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6Ol4GuVdBHA" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe> </p>
<h2><strong>Caleb Hunter:</strong>  Mr. Matles, would you please introduce yourself?</h2>
<p><strong>Robert Matles:</strong>  First of all, I want to thank you for the opportunity to spend some time with you today. My name is Rob Matles, and I&#8217;m a managing director at J.P. Morgan Chase. I&#8217;m a technologist and I work on and build systems that move ten percent of the world&#8217;s money every day.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong> What are the best qualities of your job?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> I&#8217;ll tell you that for me, the best thing is to work with some fantastic people. I can&#8217;t stress how incredible the amount of energy, the amount of passion, the amount of curiosity, and the amount of intellect is here.</p>
<p>The other thing that I really like about this job is that you can make a difference. So, what we work on you can actually see value in it. I&#8217;ll give you an example. Last year, I was working on a project where we reduced the time it takes to open accounts for big companies, from 12 days to less than two hours. So, think of the value of that to companies who are now able to open accounts that quickly and start doing business with us. So, you can really  see the positive impact you have on the economy.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong> What are the biggest challenge that come with being the Managing Director of IT?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> I would say there&#8217;s two really big challenges. One is, things happen so fast in today&#8217;s world. Software, startups, FinTechs, Microsoft, the Googles, the Amazons of the world – they&#8217;re all moving at warp speed. Our challenge is not just to work that fast and deliver things quickly and be innovative, it&#8217;s also that we have to make sure that our clients&#8217; data is private. And every day, someone comes in and tries to figure out how to break into our systems and offices. So, those two challenges,  going really fast while staying ahead of the bad guys and keeping everything secure, is really big for us.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong> What can companies like J.P. Morgan Chase offer my generation in terms of career opportunities?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> So, the big secret is J.P. Morgan has 50,000 technologists that work for them. And, we do everything that you can think about when you think about IT or technology. So, things that we can offer are: we have cybersecurity jobs, we have software engineering jobs, we have people who like to work on infrastructure, we have testing jobs, people who run programs, along with machine learning and data science activities.  We offer a vast array of opportunities in technology.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong> Where would you ask people in my generation to start in order to learn about cybersecurity, computer science and programming, so they can launch themselves into the rapidly advancing technology of today’s world?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> First of all, I think the closest thing that we have to superheroes today are people who are in technology. The reason I say that is because you have the ability from a keyboard to change the world, just with the software you write and the ability to put something in the cloud and touch so many people. There aren’t many things out there that I can think of that let you change the world like that.</p>
<p>Think of Netflix, think of Google, they all started in a garage, on a computer – and look what they&#8217;ve done. So, what I say to young folks is that the first thing is make sure you understand the principles, the science behind computer or software engineering so that you have a base grounding.</p>
<p>But once you have that, I recommend that you go with your passion – and I wouldn&#8217;t start and stay in one silo. We look for people who are well-rounded, so start with cyber, start with programming, but don&#8217;t stay there. Move around. Get well-rounded, because what we see is that the folks who excel are passionate, they love coming to work, and they do more than one thing. So that&#8217;s what I would tell folks looking to come into the field of technology.</p>
<p>And you can&#8217;t think of your career in more than five-year chunks. So, if you think of your first two years, if you can do three, four different things, that’ll get you grounded in a way that you can pivot and go whichever direction that you’re passionate about.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  As a Managing Director, what do you at look for in young people who want to work for J.P. Morgan Chase in technology?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> We look for a few things. One, we look for someone with software engineering or a computer science background. We look for people who are curious, who like to learn new things. We look for people who are very good at solving problems, who have great critical thinking skills, are self-starters, who communicate well and ask questions.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  Can you give a description of your interview process?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong>  We have a couple of different types of interviews. We interview people with experience and then we interview folks who are coming out of college who we call new hires.</p>
<p>For the new hires, we start out with some general screening interviews where we get to know you. We get to know what you are interested in, what you are passionate about. If we think that you are a good fit culturally, we&#8217;ll bring you in and you get to talk to three, four, sometimes five people about your experiences, and we look for some of those traits that I was talking about.</p>
<p>We want to make sure that you&#8217;re a self-starter. We want to make sure that you can solve problems and enjoy solving problems, and we want to make sure you&#8217;re curious because we have to come in everyday and want to learn something. People are very successful if they&#8217;re driven by curiosity and driven by themselves to push through problems.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  Is Chase always looking to diversify it’s work environment with employees and managers who are dedicated to diversity?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> Yes. Inclusion and diversity are extremely important to me. Coming from a military background, it&#8217;s second nature to me, but we actually have thirty three percent woman who work in technology in Chicago. The average in the industry is well below ten percent.</p>
<p>From an ethnicity perspective, we have resource groups. We have a group called Bold, which is focused on black Americans. We have a group that&#8217;s called Aspire, focused on Asians. We have a group of military veterans…and those are just a few examples of how we look for ways to build community and diversity.</p>
<p>In my experience – and I&#8217;ve been doing this for, let&#8217;s just call it twenty-five plus years – is that the more diverse your team is, the better performing they are. That goes back to a couple of things. One is that people see things from different viewpoints, if they come from different walks of life. And two is, you get diversity of thought. People don&#8217;t all think the same, and the last thing that we want to do is to hire fifty Rob Matleses because then we wouldn&#8217;t have people with strength in different areas. We think we can diversify more and it&#8217;s a big focus.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  One final question. Do you believe Chicago will become the next Silicon Valley?</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong>  First of all, I would say that we&#8217;re never going to be Silicon Valley. Which is fine, which is fantastically fine, it&#8217;s great, because guess what? We&#8217;re Chicago, we&#8217;re unique in the fact that we are the center point for the intersection for all kinds of industries, all kinds of people, and not in the physical world only but also in the digital world.</p>
<p>Every day, a new startup starts in Chicago. We have over 100,000 jobs in this area for technology. And if you look at the companies here like J.P. Morgan Chase, we have fantastic opportunities to not only drive business, but drive our economy and communities and really give back. So, I&#8217;m very, very optimistic and bullish on Chicago becoming a great tech hub for the 21st century.</p>
<h2><strong>CH:</strong>  Thank you very much, Mr. Matles, for giving us your time today. It&#8217;s been a pleasure.</h2>
<p><strong>RM:</strong> My pleasure, Caleb. I enjoyed the time with you, and I look forward to seeing some great things in the IT industry in the future.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 5</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 19:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6280</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>A doctor. An actor. A businessman. A reporter. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/">Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A doctor. An actor. A businessman. A reporter. </p>
<p>Four unique aspirations of four unique youth.</p>
<p>UCAN supporter and marketing consultant, Chuck Kent, had an idea to help make those dreams a reality: give youth the opportunity to have a discussion with a professional who works in the field the youth aspires to develop a career. The idea grew into a series of videos in which UCAN youth interview notable Chicago professionals about their respective careers and industry.</p>
<p>These conversations not only explore how one gets into such work, but why and how that career is valuable to the city and its people. It’s all part of our conviction at UCAN that today’s youth, even when faced with trauma, can become tomorrow’s leaders.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more episodes!</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6033 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 1</a></h1>
<p><em>The interviewer for our inaugural episode is Ariyan Moore, currently a marketing student, who spoke with </em><em>John </em><em>Starkey</em><em>, Global Brand Leader for Dove and Galaxy chocolates at </em><em>Mars</em><em>. </em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6123 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 2</a></h1>
<p><em>In our second episode, Briana Owens, an aspiring broadcaster and currently a student at Ithaca College interviews Brandis Griffith-Friedman, a correspondent and segment host for Chicago Tonight on WTTW, Chicago’s public television station.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/">here</a>. </p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6118 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 3</a></h1>
<p><em>In the third episode, Ebonie Henderson, an aspiring actress, visits the Goodman Theater to interview Henry Godinez, Resident Artistic Associate and a professor at Northwestern University.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/">here</a>. </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-6189 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-268x144.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="144" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-268x144.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-768x412.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-320x172.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-966x518.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-720x386.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-290x156.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-369x198.jpg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></a><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">Watch Episode 4</a></h1>
<p><em>In the fourth episode, Maya Hunter, a UCAN participant who aspires to be a physician, interviews Dr. Perpetua Goodall, an Associate Professor of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology at the University of Chicago.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/">Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 4</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6188</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest. In the fourth episode of our series, Maya Hunter, a UCAN participant who aspires to be a physician, interviews Dr. Perpetua Goodall, an Associate Professor of Obstetrics &#38; Gynecology at...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/" title="Read Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 4">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 4</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<div id="content" class="style-scope ytd-expander">
<div id="description" class="style-scope ytd-video-secondary-info-renderer">In the fourth episode of our series, Maya Hunter, a UCAN participant who aspires to be a physician, interviews Dr. Perpetua Goodall, an Associate Professor of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology at the University of Chicago. It’s a fascinating discussion – please watch the video and read the full interview in text.</div>
<div> </div>
<div class="style-scope ytd-video-secondary-info-renderer">Find other episodes <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cIx01_S_HOM" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h2><strong>Maya Hunter:</strong> Thank you for being with us today, Dr. Goodall. Could you briefly introduce yourself and tell us what you do?</h2>
<p><strong>Perpetua Goodall, M.D.:</strong> Well, thank you Maya, for inviting me to talk with you. It&#8217;s my pleasure to get to know you and tell you about my work. I&#8217;m Dr. Perpetua Goodall, and I&#8217;m an obstetrician-gynecologist here at the University of Chicago. I&#8217;ve been in practice here for going on 18 years, and what I do is a combination of things. I do obstetric care, which is providing prenatal care to women as they go through their pregnancy. I provide care for them during their childbirth, and then afterwards. As a gynecologist, I focus on preventive health care for women, and I also take care of conditions that affect the reproductive system of women.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong> Why did you choose your specialty of medicine?</h2>
<p><strong>PG: </strong>I think that OB/GYN combines an opportunity to provide primary care for women, and it also gives you an opportunity to do procedures ( I really like working with my hands). So, I have a lot of variety in my day. I get to see women from adolescence through the menopause, and so might go into one room to see a teenager coming in to talk about contraception and walk into another room and talk to a 65-year-old who’s dealing with menopause. Or I&#8217;ll go meet with a 40-year-old dealing with conditions like abnormal bleeding or fibroid tumors.</p>
<p>I get to see a lot of different types of patients from different backgrounds, and so I think OB/GYN is a very special experience.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong> What do you like most about your medical practice?</h2>
<p><strong>PG:</strong> I really enjoy the patients – talking to them, getting to connect with them on a personal level. Patients are sharing some of the most intimate details of their lives with you, so it really gives you an opportunity to develop meaningful relationships over time. And I take pleasure in getting to know families, taking care of moms, daughters, sisters, aunts…taking care of their families and their communities.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong> Besides seeing patients, you are also a professor – so what do you like about teaching?</h2>
<p><strong>PG:</strong>  Teaching is rewarding on a number of fronts.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s nice to see students grow over time, to have an influence on a future generation of healthcare providers and doctors, and to share the knowledge that I&#8217;ve developed over time. I also like being able to continue to develop my own knowledge and improve and grow. So, it’s rewarding both as a student and as a teacher.</p>
<p>It also gives you an opportunity to give back or contribute to the system that helped you get to where you are.</p>
<p>The other thing I like is that it keeps you on your toes. Being a teacher, you have to keep up with research and up-to-date practice, and so I think it really makes me a better clinician in that, if I&#8217;m able to explain a complex topic to a medical student, it makes it easier for me to explain that information to my patients.</p>
<p>It’s also nice to have students come along with me when I&#8217;m seeing patient, to learn from me at the bedside. It&#8217;s a special experience to be able to share my knowledge with others and help the growth and development of young learners.</p>
<h2><strong>MH</strong>: I want to become an OB/GYN. What steps do I need to take to see if I&#8217;m really passionate about becoming a doctor?</h2>
<p><strong>PG:</strong> For starters, take advantage of opportunities like this, to talk to doctors in different specialties. You may find that OB/GYN is not what you have a passion for. You could shadow an internal medicine doctor, a pediatrician, a surgeon. Take every opportunity possible to talk to different doctors in different specialties and types of practices. There&#8217;s academic medicine, which is what I practice, and then there&#8217;s private practice, where people practice out in the community, and have a little more autonomy and control.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong>  What do you think are some qualities of being a good physician?</h2>
<p><strong>PG:</strong> Number one is being a caring and compassionate person. You have to empathize and connect with people and put yourself in their position. Try to understand their situations, their communities, and be able to connect with them on a personal level. It’s relatively easy to learn technical, objective information or scientific information – but the doctor-patient relationship is founded on that personal connection</p>
<p>So, the qualities that I would most expect to find in a good physician would be caring, compassionate, empathetic, and then knowledgeable, competent and confident – but not arrogant. Someone that you can relate to and have confidence in but not feel that they&#8217;re not approachable.</p>
<h2><strong>MH</strong>: Finally, why do you think that the careers in medicine are important to the future of Chicago?</h2>
<p><strong>PG</strong>: Wow. You can look at this as not just limited to Chicago. The health of society has so many effects on other aspects of a community, like productivity, economic development, and education. If you&#8217;re not healthy, you&#8217;re not able to contribute to your community or to your society.</p>
<p>Doctors play an extremely important role in maintaining and establishing healthy communities. They provide education about preventative healthcare strategies and maintaining your health. And it’s also about treating health conditions and providing access to quality providers who care about their community.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s extremely important that people like you want to go into the field. You know, looking at the number of minority physicians, well, it’s still an area where work needs to be done. Studies have actually shown that minority patients may do better when they have a provider that looks like them. So, it&#8217;s important to have, or to recruit, people like you who want to give back to their communities, who want to practice in their communities.</p>
<h2><strong>MH:</strong> Well thank you Dr. Goodall for being here and taking time out of your day.</h2>
<p><strong>Catch up on previous episodes of “Chicago’s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today,” and watch UCAN youth interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>:</strong></p>
<p>John Starkey, Global Brand Lead for Dove Chocolates at Mars<br />Brandis Friedman, Segment Host at WTTW, Channel 11<br />Henry Godinez, Resident Artistic Associate at The Goodman Theatre</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interview Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 4</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago’s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today – Episode 3</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 18:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6114</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, UCAN youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders interview current leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/">Chicago’s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today – Episode 3</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I_R6wLo1Uas" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p>In the third episode, Ebonie Henderson, an aspiring actress, visits the Goodman Theater to interview Henry Godinez, the Resident Artistic Associate there and a professor at Northwestern University.</p>
<p><em>Please watch the video, then read the full interview, which features many additional insights into what it takes to become an actor, why studying acting is important no matter what career you want to pursue, and why the theater is important to the future of Chicago.</em></p>
<p>Find other episodes <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Ebonie Henderson: </strong><strong>Please introduce yourself.</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Henry Godinez: </strong>I&#8217;m the Resident Artistic Associate here at Goodman, and a professor at Northwestern University where I teach acting. I don&#8217;t necessarily pursue acting anymore, but sometimes it comes up, and it keeps me honest to have to practice what I teach. But I am a director. I also direct elsewhere around the country when I&#8217;m not directing at the Goodman. So, I guess I&#8217;m a teacher, director and sometimes actor.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: Why did you choose your field?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>HG: </strong>When I was in high school, theater was just something that I stumbled into. And it was really the one thing that always kept me engaged – and probably kept me out of jail [laughs]. No, but it kept me out of trouble. It was a way for me to channel my energy and my creativity. And I guess I did it, and still do it, because I love helping people look at the world in a different way, and look at other human beings in a different way.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: I did some research about you – and you started your own Latino theater group. Why?</strong></h2>
<p>HG: Well, myself and a group of actors, and especially a friend of mine name Eddie Torres, were in a show together. And we had been reading a lot of new plays by Latinx playwrights, new plays – and nobody was producing them. We realized, these were stories that were about us, and we knew that there were other people like us in the world, and these stories weren&#8217;t getting told. And we thought, “If no one else in going to tell them, then we&#8217;re going to do it.”</p>
<h2><strong>EH: Growing up, did you have any actors you idolized?</strong></h2>
<p>HG: I did. One of the actors that I really admired the most was a British actor named Peter O&#8217;Toole, who was in a film called &#8220;Lawrence of Arabia,&#8221; and many, many, many other films that I loved. There was something so incredibly present about him on film; I really admired that. There&#8217;s another actor named Raul Julia, who sadly is not with us anymore, a Puerto Rican actor that I greatly admired as well. Those two stand out for me.</p>
<h2><strong>EH:  What are the qualities you look for in an actor?</strong></h2>
<p>HG:  One of the qualities that I look for in a good actor is a kind of a spontaneity, a quality that makes me feel like that particular moment on stage or on film has never happened before. Something that just feels, no matter how many times you&#8217;ve done it, like it&#8217;s never happened before.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also a generous quality that I admire in an actor. I tell my students that acting isn&#8217;t so much acting – or acting at you – but it’s really more reacting, which means that I am reacting to something that you&#8217;re giving me. That spirit of generosity in an actor is super important, the energy that&#8217;s always looking for, asking for, demanding energy from their partner. Those are qualities that I think are important for an actor to have.</p>
<h2><strong>EH:  What’s it like to work on a movie set – and how is that different from working on the stage?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>HG</strong>: You know, it&#8217;s so different working on a movie set. When I perform in the theater there&#8217;s me and you as my partner in a play or in a scene. But then we have all of the people in the audience that are also there with us, and we&#8217;re all breathing the same air. And believe it or not, that&#8217;s real, that energy that happens with, you know, 50 people, 100 people, 1000 people in the same space. It&#8217;s a very real, magical thing. It&#8217;s almost sacred.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s very different than on a film set. Because on a film set, they can cut, and you can stop, and you can re-shoot a scene. And in the theater, you do it once. You start, and you don&#8217;t stop until you&#8217;re done. So it&#8217;s a very, very different thing. And in terms of acting, the energy that happens on a film set is really between you and your partner or partners. The camera does the rest. In the theater, as I was saying, it&#8217;s between you and your partner, and every other person, every other human being in the theater.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: In addition to being a director and an actor, you’re also a professor. What’s the best part of teaching at Northwestern University?</strong></h2>
<p>HG:  For me, the best part of teaching anywhere, but especially at Northwestern, is that our students are so smart, and they keep me honest. They push me to always be telling the truth, and they make me re-examine how I do what I do, and how I&#8217;ve always done what I do, in terms of the theater. So my favorite thing is learning from my students as I teach.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: Not everybody thinks that theater is a practical career, but what do you think about that?</strong></h2>
<p>HG: It&#8217;s not a practical career? Who says that? No, I&#8217;m kidding.</p>
<p>I would say that just because you study theater doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean that theater must become your career. When students come to Northwestern and  take my acting class for two years, I don&#8217;t expect everyone in my class to become an actor. But I think that whatever they do, they&#8217;re going to be better at it because of my class. They&#8217;re going to become better critical thinkers, better communicators, and they&#8217;re going to be more creative problem solvers. They are going to be imaginative.</p>
<p>Whether you become an actor, or a writer or producer, or an agent, or a studio head, or a doctor, or a lawyer, or “just” a mom or a dad, you&#8217;re going to be a more expansive human being, because you&#8217;re going to study human nature. That’s what the study of theater and acting really is. You learn so much about what it is to be a human being. And no matter what you do, it&#8217;s going to make you better because of that.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: And what’s the best advice you could give to a young actor – especially me?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>HG:</strong>  Especially you. I think the best advice I could give you would be to continue to fill yourself up, continue to be a curious human being, and fill yourself up with as much information as you can access through your imagination, by reading books, by seeing things, by talking to people, by being an alive and aware human being that takes in the world around you. Because as an actor, as an artist, all you have to draw on is that.</p>
<p>So continue to be curious about the world around you; continue to expand your curiosity and your imagination and your intellect. I believe that&#8217;s the most important thing for a young actor.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: Why do you think theater is important to the future of Chicago?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>HG:</strong> Theater is important to the future of Chicago because this is such a diverse city, and it&#8217;s only going to become more and more diverse. As the city and the world becomes more diverse, especially with immigrants, we need to understand each other – and the theater allows us to tell stories about our shared humanity. The more that we can celebrate those stories, the more hope there is that we will recognize the similarities among us as human beings.</p>
<p>That gives me hope that there will be peace, that there will be harmony, and that we can live together as people in a city, in a country, and hopefully as people in a world. So the theater is important to the future of this city and beyond because it informs us about “the other,” the people that we consider the other. And in learning about the other, we actually learn about ourselves. To me, that&#8217;s the future.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: This has been great. Thank you for being with us today, Henry.</strong></h2>
<p>HG: You’re so welcome, Ebonie, my pleasure. Thank you for being here.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/">Chicago’s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today – Episode 3</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 2</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 22:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6011</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest. For our second episode, Briana Owens, an aspiring broadcaster and currently a student at Ithaca College, interviews Brandis Griffith-Friedman, a correspondent and segment host for Chicago Tonight, on WTTW, Chicago’s...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/" title="Read Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 2">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HXgD_rO85t8" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p>For our second episode, Briana Owens, an aspiring broadcaster and currently a student at Ithaca College, interviews Brandis Griffith-Friedman, a correspondent and segment host for Chicago Tonight, on WTTW, Chicago’s public television station.</p>
<p>Other Episodes can be found <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/episode1/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Briana Owens: </strong><strong>TV and radio broadcasting is a very big field. Could you tell us how you got into it and a little bit about what you do now?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Brandis Friedman: </strong>I studied mass communications in undergrad and got a masters in journalism after that. Then my first television job was in Wichita Falls, Texas, which is small market northwest of Dallas, Texas. And at the time there were maybe 210 television markets in the country, and this one was 141 or 142 – which is how a lot of us start, in a smaller market and then work our way up.</p>
<p>I moved up to Little Rock…got out of the business temporarily…then Kansas City… Washington, DC. When we moved here, to be closer to family, I first worked at WBBM News Radio as a freelance anchor. Now I’m a correspondent at Chicago Tonight on WTTW, the PBS affiliate here.</p>
<p>In my current job I cover education mostly, but we&#8217;re a small staff so I end up covering other things as well. I also get to host segment interviews, so I&#8217;m responsible for knowing what&#8217;s going on in education, as well as some other fields. I come up with story ideas and work with my boss on figuring out how to tell a story.</p>
<h2><strong>BO: What are some of the skills you need in broadcasting?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>BF:</strong> You have to be a really good listener – in any journalism field, not necessarily just broadcasting. I will say, as broadcaster we do have to be able to do multiple things at once. A lot of times, when you&#8217;re doing an interview, you have to be listening to what the person is saying, but also thinking about what your next question is.  “Do I want ask that next question that I&#8217;ve got on this list, or do I want to follow up on something that they&#8217;re currently saying?”</p>
<p>And just because we&#8217;re on TV doesn&#8217;t mean we don&#8217;t have to write. Being able to write clearly and concisely and accurately is very important. And these days in our business, having a strong understanding of ethics is very important. Also, I think you need a natural curiosity about everything, in order to want to ask questions and tell stories.</p>
<h2><strong>BO:</strong> <strong>What would you say are some qualities that hiring managers look for when people are trying to get into broadcasting?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>BF</strong>:  They look for the ability to do a lot of things – which is kind of unfortunate, just because that means you&#8217;ve got to know how to do a lot, maybe even more than what I needed to know how to do when I started.</p>
<p>In my first market we did what you call “one-man banding,” where we had to shoot our own stories and edit them. So you have to be fairly familiar with the technology – and with social media, especially.</p>
<p>You probably know that if you&#8217;re applying for a job they want to see what your social media accounts are like – are you responsible with social media, but also, are you engaging in people through social media? What are you sharing? How and why are you sharing it? You have to know a whole lot more and be able to do a lot more than when I was starting out.</p>
<h2><strong>BO: What would you say has been the toughest part about your job.</strong></h2>
<p><strong>BF:</strong> I love my job, thankfully. But there can be some very hard parts.</p>
<p>When I was in Little Rock, it was around the time of the second Iraq war, when a lot of states were sending National Guardsmen to Iraq. Arkansas had sent about 3,000 National Guardsmen, and many from Little Rock.</p>
<p>In one weekend five Guardsmen died. That&#8217;s a lot. I was working weekends at the time and so that means I had to find the families of these Guardsmen and ask them, &#8220;Would you mind sharing a photo? Would you mind doing an interview so that we can remember and honor your loved one?&#8221; That took a toll – I sat in the car and cried a bit, because I’ve got no reason to cry in front of these people. My loved ones are alive and they just lost someone. But it was very hard, emotionally.</p>
<p>And that difficulty still exists today, when we cover violence – we have to do it with respect and honor and with a lot of care and thought. But it’s a hard part of the job.</p>
<h2><strong>BO: What you’re saying is a really good segue into my next question, which is, why do you think broadcasting is so important today, in the world we live in?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>BF:</strong> Some people would tell you broadcasting isn&#8217;t very important today. I disagree with them.</p>
<p>It is important because there are times when a broadcast can convey something that no other medium can. For example, the stories that we saw yesterday – the very sad and deadly weekend that Chicago had. They used a lot of video. People who were very emotionally distraught outside of hospitals where the injured were taken.</p>
<p>Sometimes you look at that and wonder if reporters are exploiting these people&#8217;s grief. But then sometimes you look at it and think, “This is driving home the point that really needs to be made here – that this violence has an effect and it hurts people.” You can write the words down, and some people, obviously, are very talented writers, but I think it&#8217;s different when you see and hear it on a TV station or a radio station.</p>
<p>[At the point, Brandis turns the tables and asks a question of her interviewer, Briana.]</p>
<h2><strong>BO: So you&#8217;re a Chicagoan – why do you think broadcasting is important for the future of Chicago?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>BO:</strong>   I think it&#8217;s so important because outside of Chicago people have ideas about what Chicago is. There are narratives… We hear “Chi-raq,” and other different things – that Chicago is just gangs.</p>
<p>People don&#8217;t see anything besides the stories that are picked up by national news, so for local reporters like you to be telling different stories, giving positivity, but also reflecting on what is happening here allows us to see Chicago as another city that has problems, but we also have solutions. And people are working tirelessly to make Chicago a better place. So I think it&#8217;s super important that we have broadcasters from here – and even not from here – who are trying to make an impact on the city.</p>
<p><strong>BF:</strong>  I agree. Nobody can tell Chicago&#8217;s story better than the city itself.</p>
<h2><strong>BO: </strong><strong>What would be your advice to someone like me who&#8217;s trying to pursue this career?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>BF:</strong> My advice would be to learn all you can, early on. And if you want to pursue television news then obviously following the news is very important. Know what’s going on. Read different newspapers. Watch different news stations and networks. I think keeping a natural curiosity about the world is important.</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t give up. Sometimes this business can be frustrating and it can tell you “No,” when you don&#8217;t think you deserved to hear “No.” So keep going. Keep at it. Don&#8217;t give up. That would be my best advice.</p>
<p><strong>BO:</strong> Thank you – very much.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 1</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 17:21:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=5868</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Youth interviewer, Ariyan Moore spoke with John Starkey, Global Brand Leader at Mars. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kmEiqsKC31g" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><em>The interviewer for our inaugural episode is Ariyan Moore, currently a marketing student, who spoke with </em><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-starkey-b9a11a1/"><em>John Starkey</em></a><em>, Global Brand Leader for Dove and Galaxy chocolates at </em><a href="https://www.mars.com/global"><em>Mars</em></a><em>. </em></p>
<p>Other Episodes can be found <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Ariyan Moore</strong>:  First, I would like to thank you for doing this.</h2>
<p><strong>John Starkey:</strong>  No, thank you. I’m excited.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong>  With marketing being such a general aspect in any business, what&#8217;s your main goal at the Mars Company?</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong>  I&#8217;m currently the global brand lead for the Dove Galaxy chocolate business. It&#8217;s a $1.5-million-dollar business that exists around the globe in a lot of key markets like: China, the U.S., the U.K., Saudi Arabia. Those are the biggest markets for the business, and I&#8217;m responsible for really developing the growth plan and the strategy for how we can grow that $1.5-billion-dollar business sustainably across the world; and how we can expand into other markets and allow people to enjoy delicious Dove chocolate in as many places as possible</p>
<h2><strong>AM</strong>: Of all of the different career avenues that you could have chosen, what do you feel drove you to marketing?</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong> I was an Economics major so I wanted to go into business, but I also wanted to learn some skills that would help me in my journey. I started out in finance&#8230;I went through the Financial Management Program at GE to really get a foundation around understanding P &amp; L [profit and loss], understanding how the money works. That was a great place to start&#8230;for me to understand the business, what actually drives it, and what levers you can pull to drive growth.</p>
<p>In my role, I supported brand management and marketing teams; when I got to see what they did every day – the versatility and really the breadth of what they worked – I knew that, eventually, that&#8217;s what I wanted to do. Because it’s often important for you to get your MBA in marketing, I went to the University of Michigan to get mine – and I&#8217;ve been doing this for many years ever since. It’s the variety of challenges, and the ability to collaborate with a cross-functional team to get products to the marketplace – that’s what makes it fun.</p>
<p>And being a former athlete, I love teams.  As the leader of the team, you work with different types of people to get everything you need to get done in marketing.  I love working with people when they&#8217;re very good at something that I&#8217;m not good at, and seeing how the collection of skills we put together really can make magic in the marketplace.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong> What do you feel are the different skills you need to lead a successful marketing team, and how can you hone those skills once you get in to business?</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong>  That&#8217;s a great question. As I say, a lot of what you do in brand management is leading teams, so understanding how to manage a project, understanding how to build timelines and pull together key inputs on those timelines from various sources is critical. You are the conductor, and if you want to make the train run it’s really important for you to be able to let the team know what they&#8217;re specifically accountable for, when they&#8217;re accountable for it, and to keep them on task (but to do it in a way where, many times, you&#8217;ll be influencing without authority&#8230;which is another skill).</p>
<p>One factor that’s exceptionally important is strong communication skills. I don’t mean only being able to dig into the details, but to communicate simply and clearly so that people understand where we are going. And you also need to communicate your vision to the organization, as well as to customers when you&#8217;re in front of them, or even to the industry as a whole, as you have the potential to be spokesperson for your business in the marketplace.</p>
<p>So communication, project management, and influencing without authority are three key skills; plus, strategic agility and a results orientation. I&#8217;d day those five things are some of the critical skills that are required to be successful in this field.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong> What qualities do you look for in someone who wants to work for your corporation – especially someone trying to get their first job?</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong> First and foremost, passion.</p>
<p>Nothing gets other people excited than somebody who&#8217;s passionate about what they do and has a clear vision and a desire to come in and make things happen. So you&#8217;re going to need somebody who can bring the energy, bring that commitment, that passion, and have it rub off on other people. That also means someone who&#8217;s a strong leader, with a history of being in leadership positions, and who hasn&#8217;t been afraid to be the voice or face of a team or an organization.</p>
<p>Of course, you want someone with real intellectual horsepower and a history of academic achievement. But you also want to look for somebody who&#8217;s shown the ability to overcome obstacles and learn from mistakes, growing and developing based on those mistakes. Nobody is perfect here. You have to have people within your organization who show resilience, show the ability to learn, adapt and adjust. A track record of those leadership capabilities and skills is what we look for.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong> You’ve built a career in marketing, obviously doing something that you love, but is there still stress that comes along with that? Or does the love for what you&#8217;re doing always overshadow the stress?</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong> There&#8217;s obviously going to be stress in anything that you do, particularly when you feel accountable for not only your business, but your people, your team, and the results you need to drive.</p>
<p>I would say that it balances out. There are always aspects of the job that are tough, and you&#8217;re going to run into situations that you didn&#8217;t expect. There will be times where you have to motivate the team or pick it up after some challenges. But you do balance that out with the passion and the excitement around understanding what&#8217;s possible. I get a lot of energy from a team that, when they work together around a common goal, can deliver results you never thought possible.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong> So it&#8217;s more of a natural stress that comes with trying to be great at anything?</h2>
<p><strong>JS</strong>: Absolutely.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong>  What are some things that I should be doing now that can best prepare me for my marketing career in the future?</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong>  Get as much broad learning as you possibly can in core academic areas.</p>
<p>You want to be strong quantitatively, so don&#8217;t shy away from taking Math courses. Also, look at Economics and Business courses for fundamentals. And because marketing is really about understanding people, understanding trends and the like, take a broad course set. Take Government courses, History courses, Art History courses. Take courses that line up with your passions – and do as well as you can. We want people who show a history of academic success.</p>
<p>The other thing I would tell you to do is look for as many leadership opportunities or collaboration opportunities as you can in college. Get involved in various student organizations, and take leadership roles. Lead a cause that you&#8217;re passionate about. Those types of things really help you stand out when we&#8217;re looking at candidates to come into this field.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong> I feel like those all are great ideas, because at the end of the day, marketing is dealing with people, understanding people and showing compassion for the people that you work with and those that you&#8217;re trying to invite into your business.</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong>  Definitely.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong> Why do you feel that marketing is important not only to life in Chicago, but also to the future, to the younger generation of people?</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong>  There&#8217;s a responsibility that comes with marketing and I&#8217;m proud to say that I&#8217;ve always worked for, and I currently work for, an organization that takes the responsibility of marketing to consumers, to children, very seriously – and doing it in a way that&#8217;s ethical and doesn&#8217;t try to exploit any communities.</p>
<p>You can think about times when there was an ad trying to target an African American community, but they really didn&#8217;t understand the African American community. We can bring that perspective, or we can learn that perspective and have a commitment to really doing our research and understanding what it takes to connect with consumers in an authentic way, regardless of if we are from that race or not.</p>
<p>To market effectively, you have to have an appreciation and a desire to really understand your consumers, what their needs are and how they live their lives. This is not only from an ethnic or a geographic standpoint, but also socioeconomically. And you need to do that in a way that is respectful and that allows the consumer to say, “They understand me, and this product actually fits my needs.”</p>
<h2><strong>AM</strong>: With business being so competitive, what are some things your team does to stand out and say, “Buy with me,” instead of buying that other brand?</h2>
<p>JS: I think we have clear values that we state in terms of how we market:</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t market to children under the age of thirteen. We have very strong environmental and sustainability goals that are within our DNA, of how we operate and what we want to do. But we aren’t this way because of consumer pressure – this is simply the way we believe, and the Mars family believes, we should operate.</p>
<p>We take great pride in consistently looking at innovation and communication that hits consumers at an emotional level and truly meets their needs. We over-invest doing research to truly understand consumers, to understand them now and where they&#8217;re going in the future.</p>
<p>From an environmental standpoint, we don&#8217;t want the way that we bring products to market to have a negative impact on our environment or our society. So we initiatives like the wind farms we’ve set up that now generate enough energy for all of our factories in North America. By using sustainable energy sources, we&#8217;re not only thinking about today, but also about leaving a positive impact for our community moving well into the future.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong> So it’s about caring for the consumer on a personal level, and not only on the monetary side of things?</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong> Absolutely. Consumers are expecting a lot more from corporations these days. Now they don&#8217;t just look at the product on the shelf; they also research online to see what your practices are, from hiring to the environment. There&#8217;s a greater desire for transparency from corporations now, so as consumers build a relationship with an individual product, they’re also making sure they can buy into the company that&#8217;s behind it.</p>
<h2><strong>AM: </strong>That’s great. Thank you so much.</h2>
<p><strong>JS:</strong>  No, thank you very much. These are excellent questions. You make me excited about the future of marketing and marketing leaders, and I wish you nothing but success. Hopefully, you&#8217;ll be sitting here one day giving advice to young men and women.</p>
<h2><strong>AM:</strong> I hope to. Thank you again.</h2>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today &#8211; Episode 1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
