<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Blog &#8211; UCAN</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/category/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org</link>
	<description>Youth who have suffered trauma can become our future leaders</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 18:50:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 18:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6380</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this episode a budding activist in the fight against food insecurity, interviews the Vice President of Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4o1OkmaWSXg" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p><strong>How to fight hunger in Chicago and around the world</strong>. In this episode, Jade Wilkins, a budding activist in the fight against food insecurity (and a UCAN participant), interviews Nicole Robinson, Vice President of Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository. They discuss food insecurity, waste, hunger as a product of poverty and inequality, and hope ­– hope arising from a commitment to community.</p>
<p>Other Episodes can be found <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Jade Wilkins: Can you tell me a little bit about your role in the Chicago Food Depository and what you do here?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Nicole Robinson: </strong>I am the Vice President of what we call Community Impact at the Greater Chicago Food Depository, and I lead all of our programs, workforce development, and public policy programs. At the food depository, we are committed to ending hunger. We are one of 200 food banks across the country who do this work and we service the greater Chicagoland area within Cook County.</p>
<p>There are about 800,000 people who show up at food pantries, soup kitchens, and shelters across our service area and we help connect them to food, to work. And we help mobilize the public and raise awareness so that we can do something about ending hunger. It&#8217;s all about connecting people to the resources that they need.</p>
<p><strong>JW: That&#8217;s amazing. When I was here volunteering last year, I never would&#8217;ve noticed or imagined that the Greater Chicago Food Depository connects people to these different resources that allow them to get jobs as well as food. </strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you so much for volunteering at the food depository.</p>
<p><strong>JW: Of course.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you for that observation about that work, but Jade, when you think about it, hunger is a symptom of poverty. And when you think about a place like Chicago, some of the key issues we deal with in Chicago are poverty, racial inequity, and violence in our city – and hunger intersects with all of those things. In our work, we take all of that into consideration. If we&#8217;re going to end hunger, it&#8217;s really important for us to think about the economic impact and how we connect people to employment.</p>
<p>One of the programs we have that does that is a culinary training program called Chicago&#8217;s Community Kitchens. It&#8217;s 14 weeks long, and people learn here in our kitchen and in our classroom about the technical skills you need to work in the food industry. Then they get placed in a permanent job. We&#8217;re really proud of that work.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Wow. Why did you to join a nonprofit organization – specifically, the Greater Chicago Food Depository, working on humanitarian issues?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I&#8217;d say two things. One, I&#8217;ve been here about three years and, prior to that, I worked in the food industry. But I’m also a kid of Chicago Southside. I love Chicago, and I&#8217;ve been to other places in the world that deal with food insecurity and malnutrition. Although it has been striking, there are neighborhoods right in my backyard where young people, families, older adults all struggle with getting connected to food.</p>
<p>When I was a kid, I received something called SNAP. It used to be called food stamps and it’s a federal nutrition program where families can go into the grocery store and get the food that they need when they don&#8217;t have enough. So I am very personally aware of what that need is and how important it is to do something about it.</p>
<p>I want things to get better, I want families and individuals, young people to reach their full potential – and good nutrition, healthy food, is a big part of that.</p>
<p><strong>JW: I agree. My family was actually a part of that program at some time. We decided that we wanted to be more independent and not rely on government help by using SNAP or food stamps. That transition did make the situation a little bit worse for a short time. We&#8217;re still struggling, but it&#8217;s really good to make that transition and start developing that individuality. I really do understand that  – and that&#8217;s where my passion for food waste and this issue stems</strong> <strong>from.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I think your passion comes through on this issue for sure.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: </strong><strong>Thank you. Can for-profit organizations be as helpful as nonprofit organizations? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>I think that, absolutely, corporations can be helpful in this effort, and we sometimes refer to them as public private partnerships, because nonprofits can&#8217;t do it alone. As an organization, we were actually designed to be an emergency resource for families, not their only source of food.Unfortunately, we&#8217;re  in a state where people come to us more than we actually think they need to, and we would like to make sure they&#8217;re connected to programs like SNAP that can get them the resources that they need.</p>
<p>But corporations are some of our number one partners, because 30 to 40 percent of the food we receive is donated to the food depository. We receive it from grocery stores like Jewel, Osco, Mariano&#8217;s, Aldi.</p>
<p>Starbucks is one of our biggest partners, and they have something called Food Share. They sell food in their stores – salads, sandwiches, fruit, pastries, all sorts of things – and every single day, we have a team of drivers who go to Starbucks stores overnight and they pick up all the food that&#8217;s left over from the previous day. That food goes directly to shelters in the Chicagoland area that are serving people impacted by homelessness.</p>
<p>None of that food goes to waste – and it was their idea to create that program. Starbucks approached us about this partnership.</p>
<p><strong>JW: That is incredible. I would&#8217;ve never imagined.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Most people don&#8217;t know that. Starbucks knew that they were going to sell food in their stores, but what they didn&#8217;t want to see was their unsold food going to waste.</p>
<h2><strong>JW:</strong> <strong>I am curious about one thing. You mentioned that there are grocers that donate food to the Greater Chicago Food Depository. I was wondering, what percentage of that food that would otherwise be wasted in those grocery stores gets donated?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> I don&#8217;t have the exact percentage, Jade, but I&#8217;d say that a good chunk of it is not wasted. Similar to the Starbucks program, what happens is the store managers in those Jewel, Osco, or Mariano&#8217;s stores, at the end of each week, collect the food that&#8217;s not saleable but still good and they save it for us. Then, we have drivers who go to the different stores across the Cook County area and pick up that food. The intent is to get as much as possible.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Right, what do you think happens to the remainder of that food if it is wasted – and why is it wasted?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> We try to get most of it, but what we also need to balance in the equation is that we&#8217;re putting trucks on the road to go get the food. So, for example, if there are only three sandwiches and you send a truck to get them…the cost-benefit analysis doesn’t really work.</p>
<p>But most times, we do get the food. And if we have partners with smaller quantities, those might go to pantry in their neighborhood. The pantry will partner with us and they will actually do the pickup of the food. I think we do our best to reduce the waste as much as possible – but it is about connecting families to the food, right?</p>
<p><strong>JW:  I recall there being an act that allows restaurants, grocers I believe, to be able to donate food.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> The Good Samaritan Act.</p>
<p><strong>JR: Yes!</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> You have done your research, Jade.</p>
<p><strong>JW:</strong><strong> I’ve delved really deep, I’m very passionate about this. I want to find a way to alter the policies that are causing all of this food waste. At my school, students have to pick up a certain amount of fruit or vegetables, and a lot of those students don&#8217;t eat that, so they end up throwing it away. I wanted to find a way other than going to collect it every day, something that&#8217;s more sustainable, something that can be carried on even after I leave Lane Tech.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong>  Did you mobilize students to collect the food that was going to waste?</p>
<p><strong>JW:  I did have a few people who were really interested in that. One student in particular saw me collecting food and they were inspired to do it as well. I&#8217;m unable to collect food during lunch because I have academic obligations. But, this one student goes around and collects the food in my absence, and he does it religiously. It&#8217;s amazing to see that. Honestly, when I saw that for the first time, I was almost moved to tears. Seeing someone else inspired by me inspired me some more.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Right, that&#8217;s what mobilizing the public around an issue is – and you sound like a food justice champion. We need more people like you to do this work. Yes, we&#8217;re partnering with corporations and government, but we still need so many individual people to be involved in this issue.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: One of my main goals in life is to establish my own nonprofit organization, kind of like what we have here at the Greater Chicago Food Depository, and I was wondering, what are the qualifications that you would need, or the qualities that make a successful nonprofit like this? </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> There are two pieces to it. Part of it is that hunger has been around for a long time, and the food depository has been around for 40 years. We&#8217;ve been doing good work, but we know that there&#8217;s more to do — and we need to get at the root cause of some of these problems.</p>
<p>I think for someone like you who wants to start a nonprofit, you need to ask yourself, &#8220;What can I do differently?&#8221; And &#8220;What&#8217;s my niche?&#8221; What is the food depository missing, that&#8217;s not being done to serve the community? I think that&#8217;s a big opportunity for you. And part of it is just being curious, curious and listening to people in the community so you get a sense of what they really need so that you&#8217;re giving them the right solutions.</p>
<p><strong>JW: Definitely. I really want to be more involved in the community and I see the community as a family –  but it&#8217;s more like a divided family.</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> That is part of the opportunity. How do we bring people together? A lot of times we talk at the food depository about going from transactional relationships to transformational. If we could just make our relationships at home, in the community, and at work transformational, we’d solve all the world&#8217;s problems.</p>
<p>In a world and in a city like Chicago, where there&#8217;s so much wealth, so much opportunity, I want to make sure that the opportunity is spread out, for everybody to reach their full potential, especially in the neighborhoods that today have the least.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: As we draw our interview to a close, I would really like to know, are there any role models in your life that have led you to become the person that you are today, involved in nonprofits such as the Greater Chicago Food Depository that work on issues like food insecurity and food waste?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> Sure. Actually, some non-famous people, like teachers in elementary school. Mr. Boyd. And teachers in high school, Carol Gehring.</p>
<p>I had everyday role models. My mom&#8217;s a role model for me. She was a single mom. My grandmother is a role model as well for me because she worked really hard. She was part of something called The Great Migration, and she came from Arkansas for a better life for her and her children.</p>
<p>All of those women inspire me in my life. But then there are so many great women leaders in the city of Chicago. One I think you might be interested in became the head of the World Food Program. She was the first African American woman to lead the World Food Program which works in over 75 countries around the world. She lives right here in Chicago. That’s definitely someone I look up to when I think about this world of anti-hunger work.</p>
<h2><strong>JW: Thank you so much for being with us today. It was really wonderful talking to you and learning more about the Greater Chicago Food Depository. </strong></h2>
<p><strong>NR:</strong> It was my pleasure to meet you, Jade. You are phenomenal at what you do, and you&#8217;re smart. Mind if I get a hug?</p>
<p><strong>JW: </strong><strong>Of course!</strong></p>
<p><strong>NR: </strong>Thank you. Thank you for coming to the food depository to do this interview.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/">Chicago&#8217;s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today Episode 6</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opportunity Doesn&#8217;t Knock</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 18:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Employees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6339</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Chase Larkin is a living, breathing example of UCAN's vision and mission: he went from passively attending a youth group to leading it. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/">Opportunity Doesn&#8217;t Knock</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chase Larkin is a living, breathing example of UCAN&#8217;s vision and mission: he went from passively attending a youth group to leading it.  </p>
<p>Chase spent his childhood in Harvey, Illinois, with his mother, grandmother and sister as well as his extended family as neighbors. On weekends, Chase would spend time with his father&#8217;s family on Chicago’s South Side at 93rd Street and Blackstone Avenue.  In both instances, while Chase was surrounded by a community of people who cared about his welfare, there also existed the external influences of gangs and drugs, something both of his parents wanted him to avoid. </p>
<p>So, when in fifth grade, his father relocated to Country Club Hills and invited Chase and his brother to come and live with him.</p>
<p>&#8220;I wanted to live with my dad and my brother. I had never had that before,&#8221; says Chase. &#8220;So we moved out there, but my mind wasn&#8217;t ready for that environment. I brought a lot of 93rd and Blackstone with me and a lot of Harvey mentality to a peaceful neighborhood. I started to get into a little trouble and my grades started to slip and my mom noticed. Fast forward to high school, my mom started working at UCAN.&#8221;<img class="alignright wp-image-6365 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-268x402.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="402" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-268x402.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-768x1152.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-320x480.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-966x1449.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-720x1080.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-290x435.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_0871-e1554404013590-369x554.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></p>
<p>In 2006, Chase&#8217;s mother, Michael Ann Wiley, joined UCAN. She met Fred Long, the current Vice President of Development, who had grown up in UCAN programming. Fred told Michael Ann about a male mentoring program called Project Visible Man (PVM), and she immediately knew Chase should be in it.</p>
<p>She picked him up every Wednesday after school and drove him across the city to the group. At 16, it was a new experience for Chase, and it took him six months for him to begin to open up.</p>
<p>&#8220;At that time I just wasn&#8217;t ready to hear it. I was like, ‘I&#8217;m fine doing exactly what I&#8217;m doing.’ But as time passed people really just started being more invested in my life. I would see Fred on non-PVM days and he would ask me how I&#8217;m doing, and Claude [Robinson, Executive Vice President of External Affairs &amp; Diversity] would too.&#8221;</p>
<p>Jason Daniels, a Youth Development Coach at UCAN, would also help get Chase more engaged in the group. It didn&#8217;t take long before Chase was fully invested. Soon after, Claude had Chase began to go on exposure outings via the Striving To Achieve Realistic Success (STARs) program. </p>
<p>By 18, Chase was facilitating PVM. By 19, he was officially a UCAN employee as a Youth Development Coach. </p>
<p>&#8220;It brought out new qualities and skills that I didn&#8217;t know I had,&#8221; he says of leading PVM. For most of his life, he thought he wanted to be a lawyer, but after being in PVM and taking a few college courses in the field, he learned it wasn&#8217;t the right fit. He realized, however, he would have come to that conclusion sooner had he taken the opportunity of a summer internship at a law office during high school.</p>
<p>&#8220;If I would have done that internship, I probably would have figured it out before I took these classes. I was just like, ‘I need to be more intentional about taking opportunities even if they may not sound fun or immediately beneficial, I need to start thinking more long term.’&#8221;</p>
<p>There was one moment that made Chase realize this was what he truly wanted to do. It was at &#8220;Learn and Earn,&#8221; a program in which high school youth attended an event to learn reading, writing, arithmetic and life skills.</p>
<p>&#8220;A youth got mad at a young lady and he punched a hole in the wall. I remember sitting down and having a very good conversation about life in general and it had very little to do with him punching the wall, but it had to do with managing emotions and being productive. We had a very good talk and when he walked away, I could tell during the rest of the program, he would be very intentional about not getting in trouble. It was that one conversation that made all the difference, and it wasn&#8217;t even about punching the wall. We just talked.&#8221;</p>
<p>After that, Chase knew he was on the right path. </p>
<p>&#8220;This is my passion. I really enjoy gathering as much information as possible and learn, and I really enjoy spreading that knowledge and see it be beneficial to someone else. My belief is that all the information that I get is not always for me. It&#8217;s selfish of me to hold on to that and not spread it along. I think about the knowledge that I have now, that I didn&#8217;t have when I at 16 and 15, it would be selfish of me to not reach out to the 13 year old and say, “Listen, this is something you might need.’&#8221;</p>
<p>After 11 years as a UCAN employee, Chase reflects on what his career has taught him.</p>
<p>&#8220;UCAN opened my eyes to different opportunities. One thing I learned is that opportunity doesn&#8217;t knock. We think opportunity comes to us, that we either miss it or we don&#8217;t take it, but the truth is opportunities are around us all the time. The reason why we don&#8217;t acknowledge them is because we are not prepared to see them as opportunities, so I think UCAN has opened my eyes to be more prepared to spot opportunities, even when those opportunities aren&#8217;t for myself.&#8221;</p>
<p>This year, Chase was honored with a UCAN President&#8217;s Coin to recognize his spirit, service and teamwork.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/">Opportunity Doesn&#8217;t Knock</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/opportunity-doesnt-knock/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>UCAN Celebrates Women</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 18:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Employees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6343</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>UCAN practices and celebrates diversity, equity and inclusion year round, and in honor of International Women's History Month held two women-centric events for all genders.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/">UCAN Celebrates Women</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UCAN practices and celebrates diversity, equity and inclusion year round, and in honor of International Women&#8217;s History Month held two women-centric events for all genders.</p>
<p>To kick off the month, the Diversity, Equity and Inclusion Committee, along with Sisterhood 180, held the second annual Black Women&#8217;s Leadership Brunch on March 27, that brought together a panel of inspiring, successful black female professionals who are leaders within the their respective industry. The panel comprised five women: Rhonda Haynes of the National Association for Urban Debate Leagues, Deborah Olivia Farmer of Brown Farmer Media Group, Inc., Tracie D. Hall of The Joyce Foundation, Cristel Turner of U.S. Cellular, and former news anchor Robin Robinson, now the Director of Community Affairs at the Chicago Police Department.</p>
<img class=" wp-image-6360 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1.png" alt="" width="380" height="283" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1.png 668w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1-268x200.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1-320x239.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1-290x216.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/Capture-1-369x275.png 369w" sizes="(max-width: 380px) 100vw, 380px" />
<p>The discussion focused on the intersection of gender and race, and the unique obstacles it can create in your personal and professional lives.</p>
<p>&#8220;We have nothing to gain by staying small,&#8221; said Tracie Hall. &#8220;I always heard friends talking about making more opportunities for black girls to be queens and princess. I always wanted to be the wizard! I wanted to do magic and have power.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Anyone can be a leader,&#8221; added Cristel Turner.</p>
<p>The next event on International Women&#8217;s Day, March 8, was Women &amp; Co&#8217;s &#8220;Celebrating (extra)Ordinary Women.&#8221; Participants explored women&#8217;s history, the history of women at UCAN, and spent an hour &#8220;speed mentoring.&#8221; They learned how to empower, collaborate and encourage girls and women in our lives (including ourselves) to embrace the strength and confidence within them/us.</p>
<p><img class=" wp-image-6368 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice.jpg" alt="" width="341" height="275" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice.jpg 512w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice-268x216.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice-320x258.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice-290x234.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/art-peice-369x298.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 341px) 100vw, 341px" />The event concluded with an interactive art piece dedicated to extraordinary women. The keynote speaker was Laura Angelucci, UCAN’s Vice President of Administration, and she went through the history of feminism and intersectionality within the movement. Participants were also treated to &#8220;A Brief History of Women at UCAN,&#8221; which in relation to UCAN&#8217;s full history was anything but brief. </p>
<p>&#8220;(extra)Ordinary Women highlighted a diverse array of talents among women inside and outside of UCAN,” says Rebecca Brown, Development Coordinator at UCAN. “It offered a space for people to connect with each other while learning about the true meaning of feminism &#8211; the belief that men and women should have equal rights and opportunities.&#8221;</p>
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6367" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404.jpg" alt="" width="6000" height="4000" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404.jpg 6000w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/DSC_1404-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 6000px) 100vw, 6000px" />
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/">UCAN Celebrates Women</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/04/ucan-celebrates-women/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 19:28:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6280</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>A doctor. An actor. A businessman. A reporter. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/">Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A doctor. An actor. A businessman. A reporter. </p>
<p>Four unique aspirations of four unique youth.</p>
<p>UCAN supporter and marketing consultant, Chuck Kent, had an idea to help make those dreams a reality: give youth the opportunity to have a discussion with a professional who works in the field the youth aspires to develop a career. The idea grew into a series of videos in which UCAN youth interview notable Chicago professionals about their respective careers and industry.</p>
<p>These conversations not only explore how one gets into such work, but why and how that career is valuable to the city and its people. It’s all part of our conviction at UCAN that today’s youth, even when faced with trauma, can become tomorrow’s leaders.</p>
<p>Stay tuned for more episodes!</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6033 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/wordpress-size-18-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 1</a></h1>
<p><em>The interviewer for our inaugural episode is Ariyan Moore, currently a marketing student, who spoke with </em><em>John </em><em>Starkey</em><em>, Global Brand Leader for Dove and Galaxy chocolates at </em><em>Mars</em><em>. </em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/10/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-1/">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6123 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-3-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 2</a></h1>
<p><em>In our second episode, Briana Owens, an aspiring broadcaster and currently a student at Ithaca College interviews Brandis Griffith-Friedman, a correspondent and segment host for Chicago Tonight on WTTW, Chicago’s public television station.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/11/chicagos-tomorrow-interviews-chicago-today-episode-2/">here</a>. </p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-6118 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-268x173.png" alt="" width="268" height="173" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-268x173.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-320x207.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-720x465.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-290x187.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-410x264.png 410w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-256x165.png 256w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-369x238.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-468x302.png 468w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/wordpress-size-1-270x174.png 270w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />Watch Episode 3</a></h1>
<p><em>In the third episode, Ebonie Henderson, an aspiring actress, visits the Goodman Theater to interview Henry Godinez, Resident Artistic Associate and a professor at Northwestern University.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/">here</a>. </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/"><img class="alignleft wp-image-6189 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-268x144.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="144" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-268x144.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-768x412.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-320x172.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-966x518.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-720x386.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-290x156.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image-369x198.jpg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/CTICT-Ep.-4-header-image.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></a><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">Watch Episode 4</a></h1>
<p><em>In the fourth episode, Maya Hunter, a UCAN participant who aspires to be a physician, interviews Dr. Perpetua Goodall, an Associate Professor of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology at the University of Chicago.</em></p>
<p>Read the full interview <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/01/chicagos-tomorrow-interview-chicago-today-episode-4/">here</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/">Chicago Today, Chicago Tomorrow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/03/chicago-today-chicago-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 17:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volunteers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6279</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>"Today we are celebrating Dr. King while also coming out to support our community,” said Nadine Toussaint, a student at UIC. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/">Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the growing Civil Rights Movement incited detractors in 1959, many faith leaders in Chicago feared backlash and refused to allow Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. to preach to their congregations. Reverend James Marcellus Stone, then pastor of Stone Temple Baptist Church, welcomed Dr. King to preach, knowing that a message of justice and love should be welcomed in his church.</p>
<p>On January 26 of 1966, one year after declaring Chicago the epicenter of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference&#8217;s civil rights efforts in the north, Dr. King and his wife Coretta moved to a quaint apartment on the West Side of the city in North Lawndale, across the street from the Stone Temple Baptist Church. Stone Temple would go on to become Dr. King’s &#8220;action center&#8221; for the Civil Rights Movement. Though Dr. King&#8217;s apartment is gone, Stone Temple continues to be a pillar in North Lawndale, the home of UCAN’s headquarters.</p>
<img class="alignright wp-image-6284 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-268x357.jpeg" alt="" width="268" height="357" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-268x357.jpeg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-768x1024.jpeg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-320x427.jpeg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-966x1288.jpeg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-720x960.jpeg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-290x387.jpeg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180-369x492.jpeg 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/IMG_1180.jpeg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
<p>For the annual ‘MLK Day of Service,’ observed on Dr. King’s  birthday, the University of Illinois at Chicago (UIC) Student Leadership and Civic Engagement&#8217;s office reached out to UCAN ready to give back to their community. </p>
<p>&#8220;We had the opportunity to engage UIC students in North Lawndale and felt that our community needed the support more than us,We build up and support youth who’ve suffered trauma,&#8221; says Andrea Lee, Manager of External Affairs Manager at UCAN. &#8220;We work with youth themselves, their families, and their community – like with this project. We had the chance to lead this service project to support pillar in our community of North Lawndale that continues to be an ‘action center’ – of spirituality and community connectedness. In addition to supporting the youth through our programs, we recognize that supporting other community institutions is another critical way to build strong youth and families.&#8221;</p>
<p>Fifty students from UIC arrived at Stone Temple Baptist Church on January 21<sup>st</sup> ready to paint, organize, deep clean, and repair floors.</p>
<p>&#8220;Today we are celebrating Dr. King while also coming out to support our community,” said Nadine Toussaint, a student at UIC. </p>
<p>Though many people across the country participate in the MLK Day of Service, the UIC students’ day of service was unique in that they gave back to the same community that Dr. King embraced as his own decades before.</p>
<p>“It was really great because some of the community members of the church were hanging out to see what we were doing and encouraging us and thanking us for being there,&#8221; says Samantha Lagestee, another UIC student.</p>
<p>By the end of the day, the volunteers had painted two large conference rooms, washed walls in high-traffic hallways, organized the storage room and deep-cleaned the storage area.</p>
<p>“I am grateful for UCAN. I am grateful for the students that came from UIC,&#8221; says Pastor Reshorna Fitzpatrick of Stone Temple. &#8220;I’m just excited today, it’s just a beautiful project taking place. I’m sure if Dr. King was alive he’d be happy to see all of us coming together in one place having a united front.”</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/watch/?v=369657973867386">Check out UIC&#8217;s video recapping their Day of Service!</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/">Retracing MLK&#8217;s Footsteps: A Day of Service</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/uiclife/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mentees to Mentors</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 15:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Employees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6181</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>At the very core of UCAN is youth development. It’s the underlying constant within each program, and of the tools used to support their development, mentoring remains one of the strongest and most effective. “Mentor” can mean someone who you look up to or someone you aspire to be. It can be someone who pushes...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/" title="Read Mentees to Mentors">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/">Mentees to Mentors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the very core of UCAN is youth development. It’s the underlying constant within each program, and of the tools used to support their development, mentoring remains one of the strongest and most effective.</p>
<p>“Mentor” can mean someone who you look up to or someone you aspire to be. It can be someone who pushes you or someone who supports you whether a family member or a colleague. </p>
<p>But for two youth at UCAN, mentor means someone who has changed their lives.</p>
<p>Seantayvia Byrd came to UCAN two years ago through the Violence Intervention and Prevention Services program. Now she is a senior in high school and looking forward to her future with the support of her Youth Development Coach Nadia Hill. </p>
<p>“I know that she cares &#8211; for real,” says Seantayvia of Nadia.</p>
<p>As Seantayvia navigates her last year of school, she’s looked to Nadia for help in making decisions about her future. Though she hasn’t applied to college yet, she plans to attend, and when the time comes, Nadia will be there to assist her in the application process and beyond. Her goal: become a psychologist.</p>
<p>Yasmine Kirkwood, another UCAN youth, shares Seantayvia’s enthusiasm for psychology.  She cites her therapist as her mentor.</p>
<p>“I just love her,” Yasmine says. “She gave me more confidence; she helped me come out of my shell. She’s my inspiration. I don’t know what I’d do without her.”</p>
<p>Because of the support and guidance Yasmine received from her therapist after her father died, she knew this is what she&#8217;s meant to do: help people like her. &#8220;Making other people feel good, it helps me.&#8221;</p>
<p>“It’s good to have a person like that outside of your family,” Seantayvia adds.</p>
<p>Nadia Hill is herself a mentee having spent most of her life in North Lawndale. From a young age, she was active in after school programs such as the Boys and Girls Club. </p>
<p>&#8220;[My mother] was very intentional,” she says, “to make sure I was very involved with community,&#8221; and that connection is a reason she became a youth development coach.</p>
<p>&#8220;It doesn&#8217;t matter who I work with,&#8221; says Nadia. &#8220;I want them to see that they can be self-sufficient.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/">Mentees to Mentors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/mentoring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Can Survive</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 22:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6208</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>UCAN offers services that focus on mental health, from traditional therapy to expressive acting and art programs, but healing is at common theme in our programming.  UCAN Survive is a new program funded via a ICJIA (Illinois Criminal Justice Information Authority)/VOCA (Victims of Crime Act) grant that is dedicated to healing and supporting victims or...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/" title="Read You Can Survive">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/">You Can Survive</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UCAN offers services that focus on mental health, from traditional therapy to expressive acting and art programs, but healing is at common theme in our programming. </p>
<p>UCAN Survive is a new program funded via a ICJIA (Illinois Criminal Justice Information Authority)/VOCA (Victims of Crime Act) grant that is dedicated to healing and supporting victims or witnesses of crime.</p>
<p>&#8220;We keep the same foundation of UCAN,&#8221; says Janay Brinkley, a UCAN youth development coach. &#8220;We believe traumatized youth and families can become leaders as well, but combine that with ICIJA/VOCA (and) we serve victims of crime. That ranges anywhere from burglary, arson, domestic abuse, sexual abuse, harassment; even if you witnessed a crime or experienced a homicide, you’d fall under this service. We deal with clients 13 and up.&#8221;</p>
<p>Janay moved to Chicago from Maryland in 2017. &#8220;I felt like I was being called to Chicago,&#8221; she says. Though she had not previously worked in a nonprofit, she joined the UCAN team in April 2018, specifically to be trained and work under the UCAN Survive program.</p>
<p>“What makes us different from other development coaches,&#8221; she explains, &#8220;is that we are like a hybrid that includes mentorship, case management and a form of counseling. We kind of do all three in one.”</p>
<p>The grant allows for 10 youth development coaches, five under Violence Intervention and Prevention Services and five under Counseling and Youth Development, the latter of which is where Janay works. </p>
<p>“We help them with goal setting, jobs, and educational advocacy. We have youth who need us to step in for parent counseling, or help with court, or help with restraining order paperwork. We are your coach, we are your mentor, we are your therapist, and we are your caseworker,” says Janay. &#8220;We want to work smarter not harder. UCAN has group programs like Phenomenal Woman and Project Visible Man. Let&#8217;s do that same group type setting with UCAN Survive.&#8221;</p>
<p>UCAN piloted a group UCAN Survive program in which individual clients come together monthly in a group setting to address and practice healthy self-coping skills, self-care, confidence, education on the criminal justice system, and encourage hope for the future.</p>
<p>“There have been a lot of success stories,” says Janay. &#8220;There was a client (and) she was a walk-in. She heard about the program and was assigned to my coworker, Ashley . The woman explained that she was walking around with three kids and a newborn baby, living in her car. That day, Ashley helped her get basic needs at the store, gave her the information she needed and helped her get into a shelter. I was in awe of that story. She was support, she was her case manager, she gave her shelter and she gave her tangible thing she needed, all within that day.&#8221;</p>
<p>The development coaches have since worked out a system in which one coach has a specified strength that helps determine which client is assigned to whom, whether helping with housing accommodations, employment or mentoring,. </p>
<p>But Janay noticed one unexpected pattern in her clients.</p>
<p>“Sometimes, what really means the most to the client &#8230; it&#8217;s just the time spent.&#8221;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/">You Can Survive</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2019/02/you-can-survive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voices Raised Stronger, Last Longer</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 17:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6129</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In 2002, lightning struck within the halls of UCAN. Three young men took their friendship and talent to new heights by founding the Uhlich Voices program.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/">Voices Raised Stronger, Last Longer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 2002, lightning struck within the halls of UCAN. Three young men took their friendship and talent to new heights by founding the Uhlich Voices program, which is in resurgence and rebranded today as UCAN Voices.</p>
<p>In its infancy, Voices was simply a way for three young men from Chicago’s South Side – Fred Long, Jason Daniels and Victor Spencer – to bond through their passion for song writing, freestyle rap and musical expression.  </p>
<p>Jason started his musical journey near the Rainbow Beach neighborhood in Chicago, playing the violin in the second grade. At the time he was pushed into it by his grandmother, but grew to look forward to the lessons. Facing the turmoil of having two brothers incarcerated, gang fights and gun violence in the streets, Jason spent most of his time in his room practicing violin and writing song lyrics.  Soon he built up the confidence to perform in talent shows at school and found himself surrounded by crowds of his peers as he practiced free style rapping in the lunch room. <img class="size-full wp-image-6132 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4980_93000759305_5482977_n.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4980_93000759305_5482977_n.jpg 300w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4980_93000759305_5482977_n-268x201.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/4980_93000759305_5482977_n-290x218.jpg 290w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p>This love of music was what soon connected Jason to Fred. Although they went to high school together, both were so focused on keeping their heads down and away from trouble on the streets that they didn’t discover their kinship until playing as teammates on East West College’s basketball team. That’s when Fred introduced Jason to his longtime friend Vic and the three became inseparable, recording dozens of mix tapes in Victor’s apartment that was then part of UCAN’s Transitional Living Program.</p>
<p>“I was a natural show-off,” Jason says.  “But Fred would not rap outside of his laundry room, Vic’s house or on the bus. You could tell he wanted to get into the rap battles I was getting into but he would never do it. So Uhlich Voices was kind of like his coming out party.”</p>
<p>For 6-8 months, the young men cataloged the best songs from their repertoire that could be perfected and combined into a published album. With the help of UCAN’s Executive Vice President Claude Robinson, they learned how to find and network with music industry representatives and secured grant funding from Amistad Foundation to start the recording process in 2004. Once their album was released, the group toured coast to coast for almost three years, performing for crowds of thousands.</p>
<p>Flash forward to 2018: Vic Spencer’s musical career is still on the rise. His album is listed on the top 40 independent charts and he has worked with some of the most lauded artists in the rap music industry, including Chance the Rapper, Mick Jenkins, Vic Mensa and Red Man. His most recent release is a feature on Ghostface Killah’s new album.</p>
<p>Fred Long has also become an example of how UCAN builds future leaders. UCAN offered him an internship after his time in care, and he worked his way through the ranks to become vice president of Development, managing a team of seven to secure resources to contribute to UCAN’s budget of over $40 million to support youth and families in need.  </p>
<p><img class="alignleft wp-image-6137 size-medium" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-268x268.png" alt="" width="268" height="268" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-268x268.png 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-150x150.png 150w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-768x768.png 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-320x320.png 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-720x720.png 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-290x290.png 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-369x369.png 369w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote-125x125.png 125w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/Jason-Daniels-Quote.png 800w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />During the height of their recording efforts, Jason moved to New York City to make a name for himself as a songwriter.  Unfortunately, he found out quickly that without extensive knowledge of the music industry, you can be taken advantage of and left with little means for survival. It was his experiences in New York that brought him back to UCAN with a deeper and more passionate interest in protecting and educating the youth we serve. Jason is currently a youth development coach at UCAN and one of the main parties responsible for bringing the Voices program back into prominence.</p>
<p>Under Jason’s guidance, Voices’ meetings allow for a fun and free-spirited atmosphere without losing any structure or momentum in its therapeutic objectives. Youth rotate every other week between learning the ins and outs of the music business and the tools for engineering, beat making and expressive writing. The other weeks are devoted to recording and allowing each young person to share their story.</p>
<p>Jason says he’s been amazed week to week at the progress our young people make. One youth, James, recently needed a push to realize his potential.  “Before we started Voices I was working with James as a mentor. He had a severe speech impediment. He was very withdrawn and couldn’t make eye contact. One way that I would try to connect with him when I would pick him up from school was playing him songs. He liked blues and some other stuff like that. I thought … let me try something with him. So I started freestylin’ over some instrumentals. It became a thing with us and every time I would pick him up he was looking ready with a new beat to try writing lyrics for.”</p>
<p>The next step was to get James to understand how to work through some his unanswered questions in his life, like his relationship with his father that had put a strain on his development throughout his adolescence.  “A lot of things that have happened to James, he is still searching for answers to. Unfortunately he might not ever get those answers. But music has helped him tremendously with his speech. Within a year you can hardly tell he ever had a stutter or difficulty communicating,” adds Jason.</p>
<p>Jason explains that the Voices program’s goals and expectations have shifted slightly since his time as a member. He plans to host performances and find ways for youth to boost their confidence through recording. But the bulk of the program focuses on therapeutically learning about life through the ins and outs of the music business, and driving home the value of being able to tell your story in a way that other people cannot.</p>
<p>“It is how I got through my hard times when my father was on drugs and I was having a lot of resentment towards him. I had so much anger towards him that I couldn’t bring myself to just sit down and talk with him,” Jason recalls. “I remember writing the song ‘Fathers’ Day’ and just crying. It wasn’t even sadness; it was a release and a weight off of me to express those feelings.”</p>
<p>Jason wants the future of UCAN Voices to provide a similar release for many more youth looking for answers to difficult questions in their lives. “The thing about music is it is a universal language. It takes the power away from those who have hurt you,” Jason says.  “And these youth are learning SO much that they don’t realize will be valuable for their life down the road.”</p>
<p>Thanks to new funding from the Chicago Chapter of The Links Inc., and a blended partnership with UCAN’s Express Therapy program, UCAN Voices is seeing growth in membership and success. If you have an interest in music, spoken word or the performing arts, we welcome guest speakers, volunteers and recommendations for additional funding sources to keep this special resource available to the youth and families we serve.</p>
<p><em>By Ann Kniola</em></p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hhhQ9u0Jpl0" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/">Voices Raised Stronger, Last Longer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/voices-raised-stronger-last-longer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago’s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today – Episode 3</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 18:24:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago's Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6114</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>In this series, UCAN youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders interview current leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/">Chicago’s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today – Episode 3</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I_R6wLo1Uas" width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>In this series, youth poised to be Chicago’s future leaders (UCAN program participants and recent alumni) interview current Chicago leaders in their fields of interest.</p>
<p>In the third episode, Ebonie Henderson, an aspiring actress, visits the Goodman Theater to interview Henry Godinez, the Resident Artistic Associate there and a professor at Northwestern University.</p>
<p><em>Please watch the video, then read the full interview, which features many additional insights into what it takes to become an actor, why studying acting is important no matter what career you want to pursue, and why the theater is important to the future of Chicago.</em></p>
<p>Find other episodes <a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/ctict/">here</a>.</p>
<h2><strong>Ebonie Henderson: </strong><strong>Please introduce yourself.</strong></h2>
<p><strong>Henry Godinez: </strong>I&#8217;m the Resident Artistic Associate here at Goodman, and a professor at Northwestern University where I teach acting. I don&#8217;t necessarily pursue acting anymore, but sometimes it comes up, and it keeps me honest to have to practice what I teach. But I am a director. I also direct elsewhere around the country when I&#8217;m not directing at the Goodman. So, I guess I&#8217;m a teacher, director and sometimes actor.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: Why did you choose your field?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>HG: </strong>When I was in high school, theater was just something that I stumbled into. And it was really the one thing that always kept me engaged – and probably kept me out of jail [laughs]. No, but it kept me out of trouble. It was a way for me to channel my energy and my creativity. And I guess I did it, and still do it, because I love helping people look at the world in a different way, and look at other human beings in a different way.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: I did some research about you – and you started your own Latino theater group. Why?</strong></h2>
<p>HG: Well, myself and a group of actors, and especially a friend of mine name Eddie Torres, were in a show together. And we had been reading a lot of new plays by Latinx playwrights, new plays – and nobody was producing them. We realized, these were stories that were about us, and we knew that there were other people like us in the world, and these stories weren&#8217;t getting told. And we thought, “If no one else in going to tell them, then we&#8217;re going to do it.”</p>
<h2><strong>EH: Growing up, did you have any actors you idolized?</strong></h2>
<p>HG: I did. One of the actors that I really admired the most was a British actor named Peter O&#8217;Toole, who was in a film called &#8220;Lawrence of Arabia,&#8221; and many, many, many other films that I loved. There was something so incredibly present about him on film; I really admired that. There&#8217;s another actor named Raul Julia, who sadly is not with us anymore, a Puerto Rican actor that I greatly admired as well. Those two stand out for me.</p>
<h2><strong>EH:  What are the qualities you look for in an actor?</strong></h2>
<p>HG:  One of the qualities that I look for in a good actor is a kind of a spontaneity, a quality that makes me feel like that particular moment on stage or on film has never happened before. Something that just feels, no matter how many times you&#8217;ve done it, like it&#8217;s never happened before.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also a generous quality that I admire in an actor. I tell my students that acting isn&#8217;t so much acting – or acting at you – but it’s really more reacting, which means that I am reacting to something that you&#8217;re giving me. That spirit of generosity in an actor is super important, the energy that&#8217;s always looking for, asking for, demanding energy from their partner. Those are qualities that I think are important for an actor to have.</p>
<h2><strong>EH:  What’s it like to work on a movie set – and how is that different from working on the stage?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>HG</strong>: You know, it&#8217;s so different working on a movie set. When I perform in the theater there&#8217;s me and you as my partner in a play or in a scene. But then we have all of the people in the audience that are also there with us, and we&#8217;re all breathing the same air. And believe it or not, that&#8217;s real, that energy that happens with, you know, 50 people, 100 people, 1000 people in the same space. It&#8217;s a very real, magical thing. It&#8217;s almost sacred.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s very different than on a film set. Because on a film set, they can cut, and you can stop, and you can re-shoot a scene. And in the theater, you do it once. You start, and you don&#8217;t stop until you&#8217;re done. So it&#8217;s a very, very different thing. And in terms of acting, the energy that happens on a film set is really between you and your partner or partners. The camera does the rest. In the theater, as I was saying, it&#8217;s between you and your partner, and every other person, every other human being in the theater.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: In addition to being a director and an actor, you’re also a professor. What’s the best part of teaching at Northwestern University?</strong></h2>
<p>HG:  For me, the best part of teaching anywhere, but especially at Northwestern, is that our students are so smart, and they keep me honest. They push me to always be telling the truth, and they make me re-examine how I do what I do, and how I&#8217;ve always done what I do, in terms of the theater. So my favorite thing is learning from my students as I teach.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: Not everybody thinks that theater is a practical career, but what do you think about that?</strong></h2>
<p>HG: It&#8217;s not a practical career? Who says that? No, I&#8217;m kidding.</p>
<p>I would say that just because you study theater doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean that theater must become your career. When students come to Northwestern and  take my acting class for two years, I don&#8217;t expect everyone in my class to become an actor. But I think that whatever they do, they&#8217;re going to be better at it because of my class. They&#8217;re going to become better critical thinkers, better communicators, and they&#8217;re going to be more creative problem solvers. They are going to be imaginative.</p>
<p>Whether you become an actor, or a writer or producer, or an agent, or a studio head, or a doctor, or a lawyer, or “just” a mom or a dad, you&#8217;re going to be a more expansive human being, because you&#8217;re going to study human nature. That’s what the study of theater and acting really is. You learn so much about what it is to be a human being. And no matter what you do, it&#8217;s going to make you better because of that.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: And what’s the best advice you could give to a young actor – especially me?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>HG:</strong>  Especially you. I think the best advice I could give you would be to continue to fill yourself up, continue to be a curious human being, and fill yourself up with as much information as you can access through your imagination, by reading books, by seeing things, by talking to people, by being an alive and aware human being that takes in the world around you. Because as an actor, as an artist, all you have to draw on is that.</p>
<p>So continue to be curious about the world around you; continue to expand your curiosity and your imagination and your intellect. I believe that&#8217;s the most important thing for a young actor.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: Why do you think theater is important to the future of Chicago?</strong></h2>
<p><strong>HG:</strong> Theater is important to the future of Chicago because this is such a diverse city, and it&#8217;s only going to become more and more diverse. As the city and the world becomes more diverse, especially with immigrants, we need to understand each other – and the theater allows us to tell stories about our shared humanity. The more that we can celebrate those stories, the more hope there is that we will recognize the similarities among us as human beings.</p>
<p>That gives me hope that there will be peace, that there will be harmony, and that we can live together as people in a city, in a country, and hopefully as people in a world. So the theater is important to the future of this city and beyond because it informs us about “the other,” the people that we consider the other. And in learning about the other, we actually learn about ourselves. To me, that&#8217;s the future.</p>
<h2><strong>EH: This has been great. Thank you for being with us today, Henry.</strong></h2>
<p>HG: You’re so welcome, Ebonie, my pleasure. Thank you for being here.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/">Chicago’s Tomorrow Interviews Chicago Today – Episode 3</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/6114/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
							</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mini Grants, Max Impact</title>
		<link>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/</link>
				<comments>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/#respond</comments>
				<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 18:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[UCANfuzzymath]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary Clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.ucanchicago.org/?p=6071</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Summer means sun, fun and no school. But unfortunately, summer in Chicago also has come to mean a spike in gun violence in too many neighborhoods. In response, to provide youth with engaging activities in safe spaces that raise awareness of the risks and positively support youth, the MacArthur Foundation awarded UCAN 12 mini grants...  <a class="excerpt-read-more" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/" title="Read Mini Grants, Max Impact">Read more &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/">Mini Grants, Max Impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Summer means sun, fun and no school. But unfortunately, summer in Chicago also has come to mean a spike in gun violence in too many neighborhoods. In response, to provide youth with engaging activities in safe spaces that raise awareness of the risks and positively support youth, the MacArthur Foundation awarded UCAN 12 mini grants to fund youth-led projects in North Lawndale during summer 2018. </p>
<p>Check out what each youth group did with their grant:</p>
<div style="width: 640px;" class="wp-video"><!--[if lt IE 9]><script>document.createElement('video');</script><![endif]-->
<video class="wp-video-shortcode" id="video-6071-1" width="640" height="427" preload="metadata" controls="controls"><source type="video/mp4" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/90111-WLS-2018-10-28-0534-UCAN-00m36s-1.mp4?_=1" /><a href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/90111-WLS-2018-10-28-0534-UCAN-00m36s-1.mp4">http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/90111-WLS-2018-10-28-0534-UCAN-00m36s-1.mp4</a></video></div>
<ol>
<li><u>Kingdom Builder&#8217;s Christian Center</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Kingdom Builder’s Christian Center held a Gun Violence Awareness Rally on August 18 where the project’s youth leaders held a uniform and school supplies giveaway along with fun activities and food to promote unity in the community. The youth experienced the satisfaction of putting on a large event and made a difference in the community.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><u>Sankofa Safe Child Initiative</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Sankofa Safe Child Initiative held a “Girls Speak Out Task Force” forum on August 24. A group of young women watched the film “Hidden Figures” and held a discussion on the topic of self-love and self-esteem. The goals were to decrease violence through discussion, education, and participation. The youth who presented the forum were empowered and learned leadership and service skills, values and commitment.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><u>SAIC – The Art Institute at Homan Square </u></li>
</ol>
<p>The School of the Art Institute of Chicago (SAIC) partnered with the Drums, No Guns foundation to host three “Junkyard Jam” workshops on August 15, 17, and 18. The workshops focused on rhythm, music, and art to promote nonviolence and peace in the community. The youth helped to lead bucket drumming classes and mural painting to use music, art and dialogue to process the causes, symptoms and consequences of collective trauma as a result of violence.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><u>SAIC- The Art Institute at Homan Square </u></li>
</ol>
<p>The School of the Art Institute of Chicago (SAIC) partnered with the African Heritage Garden to host a non-violence community celebration and volunteer workday. The anti-violence community celebration’s objective was to engage local residents to raise public awareness of city-wide anti-violence initiatives, promotes reflection upon cultural heritage and ancestry, and encourage holistic well-being.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><u>Harmony Church</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Harmony Church held a “Peace Jam”, promoting peace and non-violence, on August 25. The youth conducted an anti-violence prayer session with the community and provided members of the North Lawndale community with school backpacks, food, music, and hosted outdoor activities. The goals? Help the youth leaders build on their leadership skills, allow residents to enjoy a safe space, and support the youth leaders in making informed decisions to prevent trauma and violence in their lives.</p>
<img class="size-medium wp-image-6100 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0651-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
<ol start="6">
<li><u>Strategic Human Services</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Strategic Human Services/NLCN held many “Dance for Peace” block club parties throughout North Lawndale featuring free entertainment and peace messages. The youth participated in something bigger than themselves, gained larger roles in the community and met new people.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="7">
<li><u>Boxing Out Negativity</u><img class="size-medium wp-image-6097 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0698-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></li>
</ol>
<p>Boxing Out Negativity held a “Gloves, Not Guns” and a “Bike Ride for Peace” on July 4 and August 11, respectively and educated youth on the topic of gun violence and promoted peace in North Lawndale. Youth built a sense of team, cultivated leadership skills, provided a platform for sharing community resources, and inspired positive action among youth through anti-violence dance.</p>
<ol start="8">
<li><u>Chicago Youth Centers (CYC)</u></li>
</ol>
<img class="size-medium wp-image-6098 alignleft" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/DSC_0704-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" />
<p>Chicago Youth Centers (CYC) held a Chicago Ideas Day anti-violence “Play Streets” event and youth leaders led an anti-violence march in North Lawndale in the summer. The youth worked together, marched without violence, built a sense of community, to demonstrate to the adults see why non-violence important.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ol start="9">
<li><u>The Night Ministry (Phoenix Hall) and Loveren Collections</u></li>
</ol>
<p>The Night Ministry and Loveren Collections collaborated and held four workshops in August focusing on conversations in healing, violence, and self-love. The goals were to empower people by learning about their bodies, share skills, and heal from past trauma and low self-esteem as a result of violence. The youth were inspired to blossom into entrepreneurs in a space for creative growth and leadership.</p>
<ol start="10">
<li><u>Grace and Glory Tabernacle Church <img class="size-medium wp-image-6107 alignright" src="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-268x179.jpg" alt="" width="268" height="179" srcset="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-268x179.jpg 268w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-768x512.jpg 768w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-320x213.jpg 320w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-966x644.jpg 966w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-720x480.jpg 720w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-290x193.jpg 290w, http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/DSC_0644-369x246.jpg 369w" sizes="(max-width: 268px) 100vw, 268px" /></u></li>
</ol>
<p>Grace and Glory Church held a neighborhood cookout and hosted vacation Bible schools throughout the month of July to bring youth from from the streets to enjoy team-building exercises and skills, while improving their reading and communication skills.</p>
<ol start="11">
<li><u>Community Christian Academy (CCA)</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Community Christian Academy (CCA) held an Anti-violence Registration Fair on August 23 to encourage youth to enroll in and get motivated about school. Support from peers motivated the students and helped them see the importance of pursuing academic success. The youth acted as leaders and engaged their peers by refocusing their energy on positive and life-changing goals.</p>
<ol start="12">
<li><u>Forward Thinking Mentoring</u></li>
</ol>
<p>Forward Thinking held a festive block party in September to bring the North Lawndale community together in non-violent activities focused on unity.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/">Mini Grants, Max Impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.ucanchicago.org">UCAN</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
							<wfw:commentRss>http://www.ucanchicago.org/2018/12/mini-grants-max-impact/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
				<enclosure url="http://www.ucanchicago.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/90111-WLS-2018-10-28-0534-UCAN-00m36s-1.mp4" length="21806233" type="video/mp4" />
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
